All right, everybody, thanks for joining us, and welcome back to the Ethereum Protocol Fellowship Study Group.
好的，每个人，感谢您加入我们，欢迎回到以太坊协议研究金研究小组。
This is week two of 10 weeks, and today we'll be talking with core developer LightClient about the execution layer.
这是第10周的第二周，今天我们将与核心开发人员Lightclient谈论执行层。
So I will go ahead and let Mario introduce Matt for us, and we'll get rolling here.
因此，我将继续前进，让Mario为我们介绍Matt，我们将在这里滚动。
Hey, everyone. Hey, Matt. Thank you so much for joining. Thanks so much for coming.
嘿，大家。嘿，马特。非常感谢您加入。非常感谢您的到来。
Can you hear me?
你能听到我吗？
I hear you.
我听到你的声音。
Yeah, thank you so much for being here, man. Really appreciate it.
是的，非常感谢您在这里，伙计。真的很感激。
For anyone who doesn't know Matt or LightPlan, he's, well, not just core developer,
对于任何不认识Matt或Lightplan的人来说，他是，不仅是核心开发人员，
he's part of the go ethereum tier team that does more than just the go ethereum uh also uh some
他是Go Ethereum Tier团队的一员，不仅仅是Go Ethereum嗯，嗯
testing the ip editing and generally uh light kill and this is kind of person who you can go to if
测试IP编辑并通常会杀死轻杀，这是您可以去的人
you uh want to understand the uh all complexities of the protocol how different things come together
您想了解协议的所有复杂性如何混合在一起
i believe he has great opinions strong opinions on many parts of the protocol and uh yeah he's been
我相信他对协议的许多部分都有强烈的意见，嗯，他一直在
also working on stuff like account obstruction for many years and um today he's going to give
还在处理诸如帐户障碍之类的东西多年，今天他将给予
us a dive into the execution layer theory which he works on implementing in the go ethereum um
我们深入研究了执行层理论，他致力于在Go Ethereum中实施该理论
and if you have any questions anything uh you'd like to i'd like to get clarified uh something
如果您有任何疑问
that is we already had some questions come up during this past week so if you have those ready
那是我们在过去一周中已经提出了一些问题，所以如果您准备好了
feel free to post them in the corresponding Discord thread.
可以随意将它们发布在相应的不和谐线程中。
And when there is a space for it,
当有一个空间时，
we will ask it.
我们会问。
We'll ask Matt about those.
我们会问马特。
So yeah.
是的。
Thanks again for being here, man.
再次感谢您在这里，伙计。
I really appreciate it.
我真的很感激。
And the floor is yours.
地板是你的。
Cool.
凉爽的。
Can you guys hear me okay?
你们能听到我的声音吗？
Sweet.
甜的。
If I ask for questions,
如果我问问题，
what's the best way for people to get those to you?
人们将它们交给您的最佳方法是什么？
Is it just through the Discord and you will ask them?
是通过不和谐的，您会问他们吗？
Cool.
凉爽的。
Amazing. Thanks so much for having me. I'm excited to talk to everyone about the execution layer.
惊人的。非常感谢您拥有我。我很高兴与所有人谈论执行层。
We'll do it through the Discord, yeah.
是的，我们会通过和不和谐做到。
Yeah. So I have some notes prepared to go over an overview of the execution layer in somewhat simplistic terms.
是的。因此，我有一些笔记准备以某种简单的术语概述执行层的概述。
But if you have questions, please feel free to post them on Discord.
但是，如果您有疑问，请随时将其发布在Discord上。
Josh and Mario, feel free to interrupt me as we're going on.
乔什（Josh）和马里奥（Mario），随时打扰我。
I want to make sure we're all on the same page as we go through.
我想确保我们都在同一页面上。
And with that, let me share my screen, and we can go ahead and get started.
这样，让我分享我的屏幕，我们可以继续开始并开始。
So I came up with a bit of an outline for us to have a little bit of structure to this
所以我想出了一些轮廓，让我们有一点结构
discussion.
讨论。
And the first thing I want to do is just have a bit of an overview of the main pieces that
我想做的第一件事就是对主要部分的概述
I see that the execution layer has, and then we can dive a bit deeper into each of those
我看到执行层具有，然后我们可以更深入地深入了解其中的每个
specific elements. So let's just get started. Let's say this is week two lecture.
具体元素。因此，让我们开始。假设这是第二周的演讲。
And first things I want to talk about is I want to talk about
我想谈论的第一件事是我想谈谈
the block validation aspect of the execution layer.
执行层的块验证方面。
With the merge, we've sort of changed the role that the execution layer has in Ethereum
通过合并，我们已经改变了执行层在以太坊中的作用
before it was kind of all-encompassing it was you know doing the consensus of the chain it was
在有些无所不包之前，您知道链的共识是
ensuring the integrity of the chain it was very you know making sure that the blocks were ordered
确保链的完整性，您知道确保订购块
in the correct manner that reorgs were happening happening correctly and and all of these types of
以正确的方式正确地发生了重新发生的方式以及所有这些类型的
things that all got outsourced to the consensus layer after the merge and at this point the role
合并后，所有这些都将所有这些都外包给了共识层，此时角色
of the execution layer has become much more simplified so i like to think of it really as
在执行层中已经变得更加简化，所以我喜欢将其视为
it's just performing a state transition function.
它只是执行状态过渡功能。
And we'll talk about what that looks like,
我们会谈论它的外观，
but just to illuminate that specifically,
但是只是为了具体阐明这一点，
we can actually see in the consensus specs,
我们实际上可以在共识规范中看到
how the consensus layer thinks about the execution layer.
共识层如何考虑执行层。
So if we go to consensus specs
因此，如果我们去共识规格
and we look at Deneb beacon chain,
我们看Deneb Beaton Chain，
we can actually just go straight in and look at the,
实际上，我们可以直接看一下，看看
it's verify notified payload uh actually execution payload so there's a function called process
它已验证已通知的有效负载UH实际执行有效负载，因此有一个称为过程的函数
execution payload that's performed by the beacon chain as it's going through all of the other
执行有效载荷由信标链执行时，它正在通过所有其他
verification that it needs to do to verify a block is valid and move the consensus layer forward
验证验证块需要执行的验证是有效的，并将共识层移动向前移动
So the execution layer has really just become embodied by this function right here.
因此，在此处，执行层实际上已经被此功能所体现。
And there's a lot of different complexities of how to communicate that stuff.
并且如何交流这些东西有很多不同的复杂性。
And you can sort of see this with this execution engine concept.
您可以使用此执行引擎概念来看到这一点。
This is this way that we're communicating to the execution layer from the consensus layer.
这就是我们从共识层与执行层通信的方式。
But really what you can think about is we do some high level checks, make sure that some things
但实际上，您能想到的是我们进行一些高级检查，请确保有些事情
like the parent hash is correct, this is the next block of the chain, verify some things like the
就像父母的哈希是正确的一样，这是链的下一个块，验证一些诸如
timestamp, some others, you know, lightweight verification. And then we send the payload to
时间戳，其他一些，您知道，轻量级验证。然后我们将有效载荷发送到
the execution layer and have it verify the block. And we can actually see the lowest level function
执行层并验证块。我们实际上可以看到最低级别的功能
in the beacon chain that interacts with execution layer with notify new payload.
在与执行层与通知新有效载荷相互作用的信标链中。
So notify new payload.
因此，通知新有效载荷。
There is no implementation in the spec for the consensus layer
共识层的规格中没有实现
because what it does is it just sends the execution payload
因为它的作用只是发送执行有效载荷
to the execution engine, which is your execution client.
执行引擎，这是您的执行客户端。
And the execution client then does the state transition function.
然后执行客户端执行状态过渡功能。
It validates that the block headers are corrected,
它验证了块标头的校正，
validates that the transactions are applied to the state correctly,
验证交易正确地应用于状态，
and it will return true or false.
它将返回对还是错。
So it's really that simple in terms of how does the consensus layer think about the execution layer.
因此，就共识层如何看待执行层而言，这确实很简单。
So that is the block validation from the consensus layer's perspective.
因此，从共识层的角度来看，这就是块验证。
Let's look at what the block validation looks like at a high level from the actual execution layer.
让我们看一下从实际执行层高级别的块验证的外观。
So I'm going to write this in go.
所以我要在旅途中写这篇文章。
This is just going to be super straightforward.
这将是超级直接的。
Really no go special things.
真的没有特别的事情。
But if you have a question on what some syntax means, feel free to jump in.
但是，如果您对某些语法的含义有疑问，请随时跳入。
But basically, you can think of the stage transition function, I'm going to simplify
但基本上，您可以想到阶段过渡功能，我将简化
it to STF as taking a few parameters.
它是sTF的一些参数。
And this isn't perfect for exactly what the execution layer is taking.
对于执行层所采用的确切条件并不是完美的。
But for illustrative purposes, I think this is the simplest way to think about it.
但是出于说明性目的，我认为这是考虑它的最简单方法。
So that we take the parent block, because we're going to have to verify some of the
这样我们就会占据父母块，因为我们将不得不验证一些
transition logic from the parents to the current block. And then we'll take in the current block.
从父母到当前区块的过渡逻辑。然后，我们将接收当前的块。
And we'll take in a state DB. So state DB is, is basically just what is storing all of the
我们将接受状态数据库。因此，状态数据库是，基本上只是存储所有的
state data with respect to the current, or I guess in this to the parent block. So that's
关于当前的状态数据，或者我猜这是对父块的状态数据。就是这样
the last known valid state. And what we would return is we would return another state DB,
最后一个已知的有效状态。我们要回来的是我们将返回另一个州数据库
because this would be the updated state and an error.
因为这将是更新的状态和错误。
So if this function is to fail,
因此，如果此功能失败，
we would want to return an error and not update the state DB.
我们希望返回错误，而不是更新状态数据库。
Okay.
好的。
So the first thing we have to do
所以我们要做的第一件事
is we have to verify the headers.
我们必须验证标题吗？
We'll look at that a bit closer
我们将近一点看
when we actually go through the implementation in GoEthereum.
当我们实际上经过Goethereum的实现时。
But I'm just going to say here that if there's an error
但是我只是在这里说，如果有错误
while we are verifying the headers
当我们验证标题时
and we pass in the parent and the block,
我们经过父母和街区，
then we just want to return no updated state
那么我们只想返回不更新的状态
and we'll return the error.
我们将返回错误。
And basically what this means here is
基本上这是什么意思
there was a header error detected.
检测到标题错误。
So an example of something that would fail
因此，一个会失败的例子
with respect to the headers
关于标题
I guess an interesting example that has a lot of historical relevance is the gas limit. So today,
我猜一个有趣的例子是有很多历史相关性的是气体限制。所以今天，
we have a gas limit of about 30 million, the gas limit is actually something that's not
我们的气体限制约为3000万，气体限制实际上不是
hard and hard coded within the execution layer anywhere, there's a mechanism that block producers
在任何地方的执行层中硬化和硬编码，有一种机制可以阻止生产者
can use to change the gas limit. So they actually have the ability to change the gas limit by about
可以用来改变气体限制。因此，他们实际上有能力将气体限制更改
a, you know, one 10, one 10 24th. So if the gas limit is 30 million, you could increase it by
A，您知道，一个10，10 24。因此，如果气体限制为3000万，您可以将其增加
that small percentage. And so if you increase the gas limit from 30 million to 40 million in block,
那一部分。因此，如果您将气体限制从3000万块增加到4000万，则
you know, in over the course of a single block, the header verification would fail,
您知道，在一个块中，标题验证将失败，
because you would have exceeded that one to over 10 24th fraction update.
因为您将超过10次超过10个分数更新。
Another possibility of something that would be wrong is that you could have the block numbers
出现问题的另一个可能性是您可以拥有块数字
not be sequential
不是顺序的
and that's something that should probably be caught at the
这可能应该抓住
beacon chain layer too but it might
信标连锁层也可能
also occur within
也发生
verify headers
验证标题
the 1559 base fee would
1559的基本费用将
need to be updated correctly based on
需要根据
the last gas used versus the
最后使用的气体与
gas limit so a bunch of those types of
气体限制，因此其中一堆
things are happening there
那里发生的事情正在发生
hold on my cat is eating my
抱着我的猫正在吃我的
foot right now
脚现在
nope
没有
hey man
嘿，伙计
Okay.
好的。
Can you hear me?
你能听到我吗？
Just for a second, can you zoom in the IDE so we can see more clearly on the screen?
仅一秒钟，您可以放大IDE，以便我们在屏幕上更清楚地看到吗？
Yeah.
是的。
It's a bit small.
有点小。
How's that?
那怎么样？
It's better, thanks.
更好，谢谢。
Okay.
好的。
So that's verify headers.
这就是验证标题。
Once we verify the header, we'll just assume that the header is correct and that the environment
一旦我们验证了标头，我们将假设标题是正确的，并且环境
that the header is specifying is the environment that the transaction should be running in.
标题指定是交易应运行的环境。
and so then from there you're really just going to apply the transactions
因此，从那里您真的要应用交易
so what i want to do here is say range over the blocks transactions
所以我想在这里做的是在块交易上说范围
so this is just going to give us a loop over every transaction in the block
因此，这只会使我们对块中的每笔交易进行循环
and for each transaction we need to execute it so we'll say
对于每笔交易，我们需要执行它，所以我们会说
that we're going to run this through the virtual machine, which is the EVM.
我们将通过虚拟机（即EVM）运行它。
So I'm going to give it a block header because in the EVM, you need to know
所以我要给它一个块标头，因为在EVM中，您需要知道
the context that the block is in because there are instructions like coin base or gas limit or
该块所在的上下文是因为有硬币基础或气体限制或
timestamp. And you need to know while you're executing that transaction, what those values are.
时间戳。而且，您需要在执行该交易时需要知道这些值是什么。
So we'll pass that in through the header, and then we'll give it the transaction, and then we'll give it the state. And we'll say that if this function fails, we just have to return error again. And in this case, the problem is the transaction is actually invalid. So therefore, the block is invalid.
因此，我们将通过标头传递，然后将其提供给交易，然后将其给予状态。我们会说，如果此功能失败，我们只需要再次返回错误即可。在这种情况下，问题是交易实际上是无效的。因此，块无效。
in the execution layer it's not possible to have an invalid transaction within the block
在执行层中，不可能在块内进行无效的事务
if there is something invalid within the block that sort of poisons the whole entire block
如果块中有一些无效的毒药
and causes it to be invalid
并使它无效
if that transaction was correct we'll update our state with the result res and uh and that's you
如果该交易正确
pretty much it in terms of the straight state transition function if we actually make it through
如果我们真的通过
the whole list of transactions we can return the final accumulated state which has all of
整个交易列表，我们可以返回具有所有的最终累积状态
the transactions applied to it no error and then the beacon chain and you know you might
没有错误的交易，然后是信标链，您知道您可能会
have some wrapper around you might have some wrapper function around this um
周围有一些包装器，您可能会在此周围具有一些包装器功能
which takes in the execution payload.
该执行有效载荷。
And this would return our bool.
这将归还我们的布尔。
This would return our bool to the beacon chain,
这会将我们的布尔归还给信标连锁店，
and it would call the state transition function within it.
它将调用其中的状态过渡功能。
So I won't write that whole thing out.
所以我不会把整个事情写出来。
But basically, I would say,
但基本上，我会说，
if there's no error sorry if there is an error return false otherwise return true
如果没有错误，如果有错误返回false，否则对不起，否则返回true
okay so the beacon chain is essentially calling some function new payload it's passing the
好的，因此BEACON链本质上是在调用一些功能新的有效负载。
execution payload in then we call on the execution side our state transition function
执行有效负载，然后我们在执行方面呼叫我们的状态过渡功能
with the information in execution payload.
使用执行有效载荷中的信息。
And if the state transition function doesn't error,
如果状态过渡函数没有错误，
we'll return true.
我们将返回真实。
If it does error, we return false
如果确实错误，我们返回false
because the block is invalid.
因为块无效。
Any questions on this block validation overview?
关于此块验证概述有什么问题吗？
We get a few questions.
我们有几个问题。
What happened?
发生了什么？
Why did you pass the block header
你为什么通过块标头
into the VM.run?
进入vm.run？
Inside the block header
在块标题内
is all the information.
都是所有信息。
There's two pieces of context
有两个背景
that you need when you're executing the transaction.
执行交易时需要。
The first is obviously the state
第一个显然是状态
because the state has things like
因为国家有类似的东西
the contract code that you're going to execute against
您将要执行的合同代码
the storage within that
其中的存储
account that you might be manipulating or reading, but you also need the context, the block context
帐户可能正在操纵或阅读，但您也需要上下文，块上下文
that the transaction is executing against. And so I mentioned a couple examples, but a few more,
交易正在执行。因此，我提到了几个例子，但是还有几个
you might want to access the previous Randow value or the block hash. This is to give you
您可能需要访问以前的randow值或块哈希。这是给你的
some sort of like randomness within the virtual machine, you might want to access the base the
虚拟机中某种类似的随机性，您可能需要访问基础
base fee, the base fee is within the block header and within the transaction execution,
基本费用，基本费用在块标头内，在交易执行范围内，
you can call the base fee opcode.
您可以调用基本费用OPODE。
And so that value would need to be populated in some way.
因此，该价值将需要以某种方式填充。
And so the reason I'm passing the header in is to populate those environmental values.
因此，我之所以传递标头的原因是填充这些环境价值。
Right.
正确的。
Thanks.
谢谢。
And so the say transition function is called by the consensus layer and gets returned whether
因此，说的过渡函数由共识层调用，并返回是否返回
it's valid.
这是有效的。
it's not valid, what happens on CL?
这是无效的，CL会发生什么？
So if it's not valid on the CL, then the block is going to be rejected.
因此，如果它在CL上无效，则该块将被拒绝。
We might be able to look at that really quickly.
我们也许可以非常迅速地看待这一点。
It was process execution payload.
这是过程执行有效载荷。
So, right here, the way the beacon spec sort of works is they use asserts to verify that
因此，就在这里，信标规格的作品的方式是使用断言来验证
certain properties are as they expect.
某些属性是他们所期望的。
And because we said that this function verify and notify new payload returns a boolean,
而且因为我们说此功能验证并通知新的有效载荷回报是一个布尔值，所以
it's trying to assert that the value is going to be true,
它试图断言该价值将是真实的，
meaning that we in the state transition function
这意味着我们在状态过渡功能中
validated the block correctly.
正确验证了块。
If it's false and you fail an assert within the beacon spec,
如果是错误的，并且您在信标规范中失败了，
that basically means reject the block.
这基本上意味着拒绝块。
It's maybe not super clear how that machinery works
可能不太清楚该机械的工作原理
just from the spec,
只是从规格中
but that's how they're usually using the assert in this case.
但这就是他们通常在这种情况下使用断言的方式。
Awesome, thanks.
太棒了，谢谢。
Yeah, I think we can go ahead.
是的，我认为我们可以继续前进。
There are some questions slowly coming, but feel free to come in.
有些问题慢慢出现，但随时可以进来。
Cool.
凉爽的。
So that's the block validation.
这就是块验证。
The other high-level topic that I wanted to mention with respect to the execution client,
我想提及的另一个高级主题，相对于执行客户端
the other main role that it has in the ecosystem is to build the execution payloads, to build
它在生态系统中的另一个主要角色是建立执行有效载荷，构建
the blocks that it contain the state transitions, all the transactions that do interesting and
它包含状态转换的块，所有有趣的交易，
useful things.
有用的事情。
So we can look quickly at how it looks to build a block from the perspective of the
因此，我们可以快速查看它的外观，从
execution client.
执行客户端。
I'll talk about this more when we get to the peer-to-peer section, but essentially nodes
当我们到达点对点部分时，我将更多地谈论这个问题，但本质上是节点
are gossiping transactions over this peer-to-peer protocol.
在此点对点方案上闲聊交易。
and these are transactions that are not yet valid in a block uh no sorry not yet validly included
这些是在块中尚未有效的交易
in a block but are themselves valid so meaning the nonce is the next valid nonce for the account
在一个块中，但本身有效
the account has enough uh enough value to pay for a transaction etc so sometimes a node becomes
该帐户具有足够的uh价值来支付交易等，因此有时节点变成
tasked with creating a block that is up to the consensus layer the consensus layer randomly
任务是创建一个由共识层随机共识层的块
determines every epoch who is go like which validators are going to build a block and if
确定每个走的时代都像哪个验证者将要建立一个块，以及
your validator happens to be chosen to build that block you would tell your consensus client
您的验证器恰好被选为构建该块，您会告诉您的共识客户
hey you should build a block and here is some context with which the block should be built
嘿，您应该构建一个块，这是应该构建块的某些上下文
and so we can sort of mock that out as a function again like we did above again and go
因此，我们可以像我们在上面一样再次嘲笑它作为一个函数，然后去
and that is going to look a little bit like
那看起来有点像
a function we'll call build, and it's going to take in an environment,
我们将称为构建功能，它将在环境中采用
which I won't fully define, we'll look a bit how we define it later. But the environment is going
我将无法完全定义，我们将稍后再定义它。但是环境正在发展
to have all the information, kind of like the header had, it's going to have the information,
要拥有所有信息，就像标题一样，它将拥有信息，
like what is the timestamp? What is the block number? What's the previous block, the base fee,
就像时间戳是什么？什么是块号？以前的基本费用是多少，
the all the withdrawals that need to happen in the block, things that are coming from the
所有需要发生在街区中的提款，来自
consensus layer. The consensus layer is the brain in this case, and it's saying this is the
共识层。在这种情况下，共识层是大脑，这是
information, the context in which you should build the block. So just build the block within that
信息，应该构建块的上下文。因此，只需在其中构建块
context. That's what the environment is. We'll take in a pool, which is a transaction pool.
语境。这就是环境。我们将进入一个池，这是一个交易池。
And this pool is maintaining the list of transactions. We'll just assume for simplicity
该池正在维护交易列表。我们只是为了简单而假设
that it's going to assume, sorry, that it's going to maintain a list of ordered transactions
抱歉，它将维护有序交易列表
ordered by their value. So this is going to help us build the most profitable block for
按其价值订购。因此，这将帮助我们建立最有利可图的障碍
the execution client given the transactions that we have seen on the network.
执行客户端给定我们在网络上看到的交易。
And we'll also take a state dbn because we'll have to update that. And what we need to return
我们还将采用州DBN，因为我们必须对此进行更新。以及我们需要返回的东西
is a block, a state db,
是一个块，一个状态数据库，
because we've updated it
因为我们已经更新了
with the accumulated transactions in that block
与该块中的累积交易
and possibly an error.
可能是错误。
Okay.
好的。
Inside build,
内部构建，
we'll keep track of a couple things.
我们会跟踪几件事。
We should keep track of gas used.
我们应该跟踪使用的气体。
because there's only a finite amount of gas that we can use.
因为我们只能使用有限的气体。
And I'm going to not account for the fact
我将不考虑事实
that we can actually change the gas limit.
我们实际上可以更改气体限制。
I'll just say it's going to be some fixed value.
我只是说这将是一些固定价值。
So this is a simple example.
因此，这是一个简单的例子。
But usually as you're building your block,
但是通常在建造街区时，
you need to watch how much gas you're using
您需要观看使用多少汽油
and stop building the block
并停止建造块
once you reach the limit of transactions.
一旦达到交易限制。
That can be included.
可以包括。
and we'll also store all the transactions that it's going to go into the block.
而且，我们还将存储所有将要进入块的交易。
So let's make sure that we continue adding transactions until our gas used is greater
因此，让我们确保我们继续添加交易，直到使用的气体更大
than 30 million. This is roughly what the gas limit is on mainnet today.
超过3000万。这大约是当今主网上的气体限制。
So to get our first transaction or to get any transaction, we have to ask the transaction pool,
因此，要获得我们的第一笔交易或进行任何交易，我们必须询问交易池，
which again, for black boxing to say that it's going to keep an ordered list of transactions
再说一次，黑拳击说它将保留有序的交易列表
for us so that we're always getting the best next transaction. And what we can say is just
对于我们来说，我们总是得到最好的下一笔交易。我们可以说的只是
to pop a transaction, we'll think of it as like some type of, you know, list that allows us to pop,
为了启动交易，我们将其视为某种类型的列表，使我们能够弹出，
we'll pop that transaction, and then we will execute it. Let's call this gas you know,
我们将弹出该交易，然后我们将执行它。让我们称之为您知道的气体，
it's already named it um let's call it gas and error and we're going to run the transaction
它已经命名为um，我们称其为气体和错误，我们将运行交易
again kind of like we did above
再次像我们上面一样
so i'm going to pass it in the environment we could just you know assume that run is
因此，我将在环境中通过它，只是您知道运行是
it is requiring some interface that both block and the environment satisfy.
它需要一些阻止和环境满足的接口。
So we'll pass it in the environment, we'll pass in that transaction,
因此，我们将在环境中通过它，我们将通过该交易，
and then we'll pass in the state.
然后我们将通过该州。
And so it's again going to run the transaction in that context
因此，它将再次在这种情况下运行交易
that the environment is defining, and it's going to return us
环境正在定义，它将返回我们
an updated state to actually accumulate the transaction.
更新的状态实际积累了交易。
So if that is not successful, meaning the run return an error,
因此，如果那不成功，则意味着运行返回错误，
we're actually just going to continue here so what this means is the transaction is invalid
实际上，我们只是要继续这里，所以这意味着交易无效
and because we still have potentially more gas to consume within the block
而且因为我们仍然有更多的气体可以在块内消耗
we don't want to return an area because um there's no error that's really occurred within the
我们不想返回一个区域，因为UM没有发生的错误
uh there's really no error that that's occurred within the block yet it's very possible that for
呃，确实没有错误的错误，但很有可能
some reason we have an invalid transaction because it did something bad while it was executing
我们有无效的交易，因为它在执行时做得不好
but or maybe the the transaction pool has become like slightly outdated
但是，或者也许交易池变得有些过时
what we'll do here is just allow ourselves to continue
我们在这里做的就是让自己继续
and try to get the next transaction from the pool into this block.
并尝试将下一个从池中的交易进入此块。
So once that we verify that there's not an error running that transaction,
因此，一旦我们验证了运行该事务的错误，
we can actually add that gas to our gas used.
实际上，我们可以将这种气体添加到使用的气体中。
So we'll just add that.
因此，我们只会添加。
So now let's say that we had a transaction which was a simple transfer.
因此，现在假设我们进行了一项简单转让的交易。
Simple transfers cost only 21,000 gas.
简单的传输仅花费21,000天气。
we would now have our gas used go from zero to 21,000.
现在，我们使用的汽油从零到21,000。
And so we would just keep doing this process
因此，我们将继续这样做
until we get to 30 million, I should probably say,
直到我们达到3000万，我可能应该说，
or the pool is empty.
或游泳池是空的。
The pool is not empty.
游泳池不是空的。
So either we fill the block completely
所以我们要么完全填充块
or we run out of potential transactions to include.
或者我们用完了潜在的交易。
and once we do that what we need to do is we need to finalize this whole
一旦我们做到了，我们需要做的就是要完成整个
transition and return our block our state db and our error and i will just sort of outsource this
过渡并返回我们的状态数据库和我们的错误，我只会将其外包
to another function we have in go ethereum something that's kind of like this finalize
对于我们在以太坊中的另一个功能，就像这样最终确定了
and what finalize does is it takes a bunch of transactions and some information about
最终确定的是需要大量交易和一些有关
the block and it produces a fully assembled block. And the reason that we do this is there's some
块并产生一个完全组装的块。我们这样做的原因是有一些
calculations that need to be done at the end of the block. I'm glossing over it a bit here. We'll
需要在块末尾完成的计算。我在这里有点掩饰。出色地
see when we look at the process function. But basically, in the header, you have things like
查看何时查看过程功能。但基本上，在标题中，您有类似的东西
the transaction route, the receipts route, the withdrawals route. These are values that you need
交易路线，收据路线，提款路线。这些是您需要的值
to calculate by merkle-izing a list.
通过merkle-wibs列表来计算。
And so what we can imagine is this finalized function
因此，我们可以想象的是最终的功能
is going to do that.
要这样做。
So we can, I forgot to append these transactions actually.
因此，我们可以，我忘了实际上附加这些交易。
So we would have to say append.
因此，我们不得不说附加。
So now we have a list of our transactions.
因此，现在我们有了交易列表。
Oops.
糟糕。
So I'm going to finalize this block that we're building
因此，我将最终确定我们正在建造的块
with the environment, the transactions, and the state.
与环境，交易和国家。
And I'll just say that finalize is going to return those three values as well.
我只是说最终确定也将返回这三个值。
So it's going to assemble the block, it's going to return the state
因此，它将组装块，它将返回状态
after it's been correctly updated, maybe with some withdrawals or something else.
正确更新后，也许有一些提款或其他东西。
And if something goes wrong during the finalization, it'll return an error.
而且，如果在最终确定过程中出现问题，它将返回错误。
So this is a super simplified way of building a block.
因此，这是构建块的超级简化方法。
So hopefully this sort of conveys to you how the execution layer thinks about building the block.
因此，希望这种对您的执行层如何思考建立块的方式。
I don't know if there's any questions on this example here.
我不知道此示例是否有任何问题。
Yeah, it looks like we've got a few questions in the chat here.
是的，看来我们在这里的聊天中有一些问题。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
Paul asks, is the transaction pool ordered in any way?
保罗问，交易池是否以任何方式订购？
If not, how do we ensure maximum profit when using pool.pop?
如果不是，使用poop.pop时，我们如何确保最大利润？
Yeah, exactly.
是的，到底是。
So the transaction pool is, and we're assuming in this case,
因此，交易池是，我们在这种情况下假设
it is ordered by basically the gas price.
它基本上是气价订购的。
With 1559, it's a bit more complicated because we have this concept of tip,
有了1559年，它有些复杂，因为我们有这个小费的概念，
but essentially it's ordered by the highest paying transactions to the builder.
但从本质上讲，它是由向建筑商的最高付款交易订购的。
So every time you call pop, you're getting the transaction that is giving you the most value per gas.
因此，每次打电话给POP时，您都会获得为您提供最大价值的交易。
Great, thank you.
太好了，谢谢。
721 Orbit asks, while building blocks, does the execution layer reject any transactions before sending it to the consensus layer?
721 Orbit在构建块时询问执行层在将其发送到共识层之前是否拒绝任何交易？
so the only time that you would reject a transaction is if it is invalid for some
因此，您唯一拒绝交易的时间是，如果某些交易无效
reason and you can sort of see that here in this case generally the transaction pool itself is
原因，您可以看到在这种情况下，事务池本身通常是
doing some verification so we're verifying more or less that the transaction is valid
进行一些验证，因此我们或多或少验证交易有效
sometimes there can be some race conditions where the pool hasn't quite updated but the blockhead
有时可能会有一些种族条件，泳池还没有完全更新，但是块状
has been updated, or maybe a transaction. In general, yeah, I mean, in general, though,
已更新，或者可能是一项交易。总的来说，我的意思是，总的来说
the transaction pool should should really verify the transaction is valid. So this doesn't really
交易池应真正验证交易有效。所以这不是真的
occur too much. But you're not going to look at a transaction and reject it for any other reason,
发生太多。但是，您不会看交易并出于任何其他原因拒绝交易，
then it can't pay. Because if a transaction can pay, then any quote unquote, invalid transaction
然后它无法付款。因为如果交易可以付款，那么任何报价毫不Quote，无效的交易
during execution is really a reverted transaction,
在执行过程中确实是一项恢复交易，
which is valid from the consensus's perspective.
从共识的角度来看，这是有效的。
It just may not have validly changed the states
它可能没有有效改变状态
beyond paying for the gas that it used.
除了支付使用的汽油费用。
One other question is,
另一个问题是，
there was some talk about encrypted mempools.
有一些关于加密的备忘录的讨论。
One, how viable is that?
一，那有多可行？
And two, since block transactions are ordered by gas,
二，由于块交易是通过气体排序的
is gas unencrypted in such a design?
在这样的设计中，气体未加密吗？
yeah i mean this is a pretty challenging problem i think a lot of people have looked at this and
是的，我的意思是，这是一个非常具有挑战性的问题，我认为很多人已经看过这个问题
there are different ideas about how to do it the proposals i've seen mostly on other chains i think
关于如何做的想法不同，我认为我主要在其他连锁店上看到的建议
cosmos for encrypted mempools have had things like gas unencrypted because you when you're
加密的Mempools的宇宙已经有诸如AS诸如AS的东西之类的东西，因为当您的时候您
building the block you don't know what the transaction is yet you're sort of uh committing
构建块您不知道交易是什么
to an ordered list of a block
到一个块的有序列表
and therefore you need to have an idea
因此，您需要有一个主意
of how much gas that block is using.
该块使用多少气体。
I've also, I think, seen some proposals
我认为，我也看到了一些建议
where the sender is also unencrypted
发件人也未加密的地方
and it's just the target and data
这只是目标和数据
that they're doing is encrypted.
他们正在做的是加密的。
That way they can somehow verify.
这样，他们可以以某种方式验证。
I guess they can do a very simple verification
我想他们可以做一个非常简单的验证
that the sender can pay for the unencrypted gas.
发件人可以为未加密的天然气付费。
So these are obviously riddled with drawbacks, because if you're trying to have an encrypted
因此，这些显然会带有缺点，因为如果您想加密
mempool, and you're trying to have private transaction flow, you are leaking a lot of
mempool，您正在尝试拥有私人交易流，您正在泄漏很多
information by even just saying gas used, and even more so if you have the sender address.
即使只是说使用的汽油，如果您有发件人地址，则信息。
So just, you know, from Ethereum's perspective, I think it probably is something that's a
因此，从以太坊的角度来看，我认为这可能是
lot farther in the future something that we probably want a complete solution and not something
将来更远的东西我们可能想要一个完整的解决方案，而不是一些东西
that is only doing most of the things right i could be i could be off a bit here this isn't
那只是在做大多数事情，我可以是我可以在这里有点不在
something i haven't looked at in a while but that's that's generally been my understanding
我有一段时间没有看的东西，但这通常是我的理解
it doesn't seem like we figure out a way to do encrypted mempools completely in an efficient way
似乎我们没有找到一种完全以有效的方式进行加密的备忘录的方法
and so we're waiting for that to be cracked
因此，我们正在等待破解
Awesome, thank you
太棒了，谢谢
There is a condition you used
您使用的条件
for gas being less than 30 million
对于汽油少于3000万
but you also mentioned it's not hard-coded
但是您也提到它不是硬编码的
so this is just an example
所以这只是一个例子
of parameter being passed
通过的参数
Yeah, I mean
是的，我的意思是
we could say gas limit
我们可以说气体限制
I think the function that we have is
我认为我们拥有的功能是
I mean, really what we could say
我的意思是，我们真的可以说
is we could just say it's in the environment
我们可以说这在环境中吗
but basically
但基本上
whenever you're building a block you your node has that ability like i said to
每当您构建一个块时，您的节点都具有我所说的那种能力
control the gas limit by one over 1024 so i could manipulate it on either end
将气体限制控制超过1024，以便我可以在任一端进行操纵
i could make it plus or minus that value and so what you would say on your client you might pass
我可以使它加上或减去该价值，所以您在客户上说的话您可能会通过
something like gas targets. I forget, I forget what this flag is called. It's gas limit target
类似于气体目标。我忘记了，我忘记了这个标志的叫什么。这是气体限制目标
or something like that. Um, and you could say 40 million, maybe. So if your gas limit target is
或类似的东西。嗯，也许您可​​能会说4000万。因此，如果您的气体限制目标是
above the parent blocks, gas limits, then environment doc, like gas limit would be
在父块上方，气体限制，然后是环境文档，例如气体限制
calculated at some point where it would try and figure out how close can we get to our targets?
在某个时候试图弄清楚我们能与目标有多近的地方进行计算？
and it's basically just taking the it's trying to it does one over 1024 to see is that the target
基本上，它只是将它试图做一个超过1024的目标，即
did we overshoot the target if it's not quite the target or sorry if it's over the target then we
如果目标不是目标，我们是否超越了目标，如果它超出了目标
could reduce it and be less than one over 1024 of a delta and you know exactly equal our target
可以减少它，少于1024超过1024，而您完全知道我们的目标
so in this case if our target was 40 million and the last value was 30 million then it would be
因此，在这种情况下，如果我们的目标是4000万，最后一个价值为3000万，那将是
30 million times
3000万次
I mean 1025
我的意思是1025
over 1024
超过1024
essentially
本质上
so your node
所以你的节点
has a bit of control over what the gas limit
对气体限制有一点控制
is for this example I'm not really
是这个示例，我不是真的
going super deep on how it's
对它的状态非常深入
computed but we can
计算但我们可以
in just a second unless there are more questions
在短短一秒钟内，除非还有更多问题
yeah they kind of keep coming in but I'm just trying to uh it's a more more important one I
是的，他们有点不断进来，但我只是想吧，这是一个更重要的我
guess um yeah interesting question was whether there are any race conditions to worry about here
猜猜是的有趣的问题是，这里是否有任何种族条件要担心
uh like transactions from the mem who will be included in the block and uh they have to be
嗯，像MEM的交易一样，他们将被包括在街区中
deleted before you build another book yeah i mean we try to avoid the race conditions it's
在您构建另一本书之前已删除，是的，我的意思是我们试图避免种族条件
i mean this is just like a toy example so it's not really addressing any of those problems but
我的意思是，这就像一个玩具示例一样，所以它并没有真正解决任何问题
that's kind of where like the integrity might be lost the transaction pool is supposed to be doing
这是一种像诚信可能会丢失的地方，应该在交易池
a lot of transaction validation generally once you get to this point that transaction should be valid
一旦您到达交易应该有效的，很多交易验证通常
but sometimes the pool you know the pool is not always perfectly in sync and it's may be updating
但是有时候，您知道游泳池并不总是完全同步的池，并且可能正在更新
or like going through its list of transactions
或喜欢浏览其交易列表
and trying to update the transactions that are valid.
并尝试更新有效的交易。
And so you might get something
所以你可能会得到一些东西
that hasn't been updated for the current head.
目前的头部尚未更新。
And so then the transaction could be invalid.
因此，交易可能无效。
That's like an example.
这就像一个例子。
But our transaction,
但是我们的交易，
our block building is a lot more complicated
我们的街区建筑要复杂得多
and there are some things that have to avoid.
而且有些事情必须避免。
Awesome. Yeah. And people are not sure what the res variable means, whether it's
惊人的。是的。人们不确定res变量是什么意思
the new state.
新状态。
Sorry, this is the new state. I think I forgot to, yeah, I forgot to accumulate
抱歉，这是新状态。我想我忘了，是的，我忘了积累
it. So basically res is the state with the transaction applied to it. And so what I'm
它。因此，基本上是RES是将交易应用于其的状态。那我是什么
doing is if that transaction was valid, then I just update the state variable to res. So
这样做是，如果该交易有效，那么我只是将状态变量更新到res。所以
But then state becomes the next state that has that transaction applied to it.
但是随后，状态成为将交易适用于其的下一个状态。
Right.
正确的。
Okay, awesome.
好吧，很棒。
Yeah, thanks a lot, Matt.
是的，非常感谢，马特。
I think we can move forward.
我认为我们可以前进。
Sweet.
甜的。
So that's, you know, we're over halfway in, but now we're done with the overview.
因此，您知道，我们已经结束了一半，但是现在我们已经完成了概述。
So let's just jump in and look a little bit more at the state transition function.
因此，让我们跳进去，看看状态过渡功能。
so i gave you a really high level overview about what the
所以我给了你一个非常高的概述
state transition function looks like but i want to actually walk us through
状态过渡功能看起来像，但我想真正带我们穿越
what happens in go ethereum it might be a bit difficult since you guys can't unmute
在Go Ethereum中发生的事情可能有点困难，因为你们不能取消静音
to ask questions but i'm just going to go through this and hopefully this is a way for you to sort
提出问题，但我只是要经历这个问题，希望这是您分类的一种方式
of see where it is this code live, what is the shape of these things, and maybe on your own time,
查看此代码的现存位置，这些事物的形状是什么，也许是在您自己的时间上，
go through it a bit more in depth and try to really understand that the flow and every line
深入浏览它，并尝试真正了解流程和每一行
that's happening. But we'll just go through it kind of quickly here. Because I do have a couple
那正在发生。但是，我们将在这里很快进行。因为我确实有一对
other things to talk about. Okay, so if I go into go Ethereum, we can actually look at that function,
其他要谈论的事情。好的，所以如果我进入以太坊，我们实际上可以看一下该功能，
that notify new payload function that the beacon chain is calling
通知新有效载荷功能，信标链正在调用
to interact with the execution layer.
与执行层交互。
And to do that, we would go to Catalyst,
为此，我们会去催化剂，
which is our name for the engine API.
这是我们的引擎API的名字。
The engine API is that interface that connects the consensus layer
引擎API是连接共识层的接口
to the execution layer.
到执行层。
And we'll go to API.go.
我们将前往API.GO。
There's a function called new payload.
有一个称为新有效载荷的函数。
So new payload here is what the beacon chain is calling.
因此，新的有效载荷是信标连锁店所呼唤的。
So it's taking in a bunch of values,
因此，它吸收了很多价值观，
and mostly the values that I was talking about,
主要是我在谈论的价值观，
the block data is in this executable data.
块数据在此可执行数据中。
And this looks a lot like a block.
这看起来很像一个街区。
It's got the parent hash, the state root, the receipts root,
它有父母哈希，状态根，收据root，
the number, the gas limit, gas used, your transactions, the withdrawals, a bunch of other
数量，气体限制，使用的气体，您的交易，提款，一堆其他
stuff. I'm not going to go too deeply into the 4844 things because that's just making stuff a
东西。我不会太深入4844件事，因为那只是使东西成为
lot more complicated. But what happens is the consensus layer got a block. It wants to ask the
更复杂。但是发生的是共识层有一个块。它想问
execution layer, was that block valid? The execution layer does a bunch of verification
执行层，该块有效吗？执行层进行一堆验证
about that block information.
关于该块信息。
So this is going to perform some integrity checks.
因此，这将执行一些完整性检查。
Like, if I hash all of the data that you gave me,
就像，如果我掌握了您给我的所有数据，
is it going to equal the block hash you also gave me?
它会等于您也给我的块哈希吗？
This is something that catches small bugs in clients often.
这是经常会捕获小小的错误的东西。
And eventually, it just goes through and verifies some,
最终，它只是通过并验证了一些
it just does a bunch of integrity checks,
它只是进行了一堆完整性检查，
a bunch of edge cases with respect to the communication between the beacon chain and
关于信标链之间的通信和
consensus layer. But eventually, we get down to this function, insert block without set head.
共识层。但是最终，我们掌握了此功能，插入没有设定头的块。
And so here, it's where we actually start trying to put that block into our chain,
因此，在这里，我们实际上开始尝试将该障碍物放入我们的链条中，
we validated a bunch of invariants that we want to exist before we start putting that block into
我们验证了一堆我们想要存在的不变性，然后才开始将该块放入
the chain and then we have to jump in and like just go ahead and do it so these functions are
连锁
pretty complicated and they are you know they have a lot of stuff that i think we could probably look
非常复杂，他们知道他们有很多我认为我们可以看的东西
at removing now that the beacon chain is doing a lot of the reorganization and chain management for
现在删除信标连锁店正在做很多重组和连锁管理
us but it's sort of an artifact of the of the fact that we used to have to do this ourselves
我们，但这是我们过去必须自己做的事实的一种事实
before we were on proof of stake so insert chain is going to call some things that we talked
在我们有股份证明之前，插入链将调用我们谈论的一些事情
about. There's a function called verify headers. And verify headers is a function that's on an
关于。有一个称为验证标头的函数。并且验证标头是一个函数
interface. The interface is defined in consensus, which is where we are, but there's a consensus
界面。界面在共识中定义，这是我们所在的地方，但是有一个共识
engine for the beacon chain, and it it has its function verify header. And what it can do is it
信标链的引擎，其功能验证标头。它能做的就是
it will perform the header verifications that are relevant for this type of consensus.
它将执行与此类共识相关的标题验证。
The first thing that it does is it checks to see is the terminal total difficulty reached?
它要做的第一件事是查看终端总困难吗？
This was the way that we determine whether or not a chain was proof of work or proof of stake.
这就是我们确定链条是否是工作证明或股份证明的方式。
point it's always you know quote-unquote reached because there is no more updates to the difficulty
指点总是您知道到达报价unquote，因为难度不再有更新
the uh the merge has happened and so we're always skipping over the eth1 header verification and
合并已经发生了，所以我们一直在跳过ETH1标头验证和
we're just doing the beacon header verification so the beacon header header verification is
我们只是在进行Beacon标题验证
pretty identical in a lot of ways you can go through the in very individual
在很多方面都相同
the individual constraints.
个人约束。
I'll mention some interesting ones.
我会提到一些有趣的。
For one, in proof of stake,
首先，为了证明股份
there's no more concept of uncles.
没有更多的叔叔概念。
An uncle is a duplicate block at the same block height.
叔叔是相同块高度的重复块。
We had this in proof of work
我们有工作证明
because sometimes if you had a bunch of distributed miners
因为有时如果您有很多分布式矿工
around the world,
世界各地，
two miners might find a block at roughly the same time
两个矿工可能会大约同时找到一个街区
before they communicate to the other
在他们与对方交流之前
that they had found a block.
他们找到了一个街区。
And so now you have two blocks at the same block number
因此，现在您在同一块号上有两个块
and you want to still reward both of those miners
而且您仍然想奖励这两个矿工
because they put the work in and they found a block,
因为他们把作品放进去，他们找到了一个障碍，所以
but only one of those blocks can become canonicalized,
但是，其中只有一个可以成为规范化的块，
meaning that it's part of the canonical chain, the chain.
这意味着它是规范链的一部分。
And in proof of stake, we don't have that concept anymore.
为了证明股份，我们不再有这个概念了。
And so in the execution layer,
因此，在执行层中，
we force the uncle hash to always be an empty uncle hash,
我们强迫叔叔哈希永远成为一个空的叔叔哈希，
which is just the Merkle root of an empty list.
这只是一个空列表的默克尔根。
So if it's not that, then we have to just return an error because that's not a valid proof-of-stake block.
因此，如果不是这样，那么我们只需要返回错误，因为那不是有效的销售证明块。
Similarly with difficulty, we don't have proof-of-work anymore.
同样，在困难方面，我们没有工作证明。
The header difficulty always just has to be zero.
标题难度总是必须为零。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
Okay, so then we talked a bit about 1559, and we talked a bit about the gas limit.
好的，所以我们谈论了1559年，我们谈论了气体限制。
This is where this check happens.
这是发生此检查的地方。
So we have to verify that the gas limit is staying within the allowed bound.
因此，我们必须验证气体限制是否停留在允许的装订范围内。
And I think that's happening here.
我认为这正在这里发生。
So we give it, okay, the parent gas limit with some value.
因此，我们将其给予一定价值的母体气体限制。
Here is the gas limit now for this current header.
这是现在的当前标头的气体限制。
And we have to make sure that it's still within the bounds that's acceptable.
而且我们必须确保它仍在可以接受的范围内。
So basically, we just compute that gas limit bound divisor, and we just make sure that the difference is not greater or less than what the limit should be.
因此，基本上，我们只是计算出气体限制的分隔线，而我们只是确保差异不大于或小于限制。
So that's that 1024 number.
这就是1024号。
We're just dividing the previous gas limit by that and making sure the difference is not greater than that.
我们只是将以前的气体限制除外，并确保差异并不大于此。
So that's verifying the gas limit.
这就是验证气体限制。
it. And then there's the 1559 logic where we calculate the base fee. We're making sure that
它。然后是1559逻辑，我们计算基本费用。我们确保
the headers base fee is equal to what we expect that base fee to be. So we're essentially going
标题基本费用等于我们期望的基本费用。所以我们本质上要去
through every single field in the header and making sure that all of those fields are correct.
通过标头中的每个字段，并确保所有这些字段都是正确的。
So that's mostly the header verification. Once the header is verified, we can actually go
因此，这主要是标题验证。一旦验证了标头，我们实际上可以去
and we can execute the block or process the block.
我们可以执行块或处理块。
I'm just jumping back up.
我只是跳回去。
So now we're back in that function, insert block,
因此，现在我们又回到了该功能，插入块，
insert block without set head.
插入无固定头的块。
And so if we continue going down,
因此，如果我们继续下降，
there's a bunch of other logic to deal with reorging,
还有许多其他逻辑可以处理重新修饰，
blocks that we already know, blocks that we already know about.
我们已经知道的障碍是我们已经知道的障碍。
But eventually, if we go down past all of this,
但是最终，如果我们过去了所有这些，
there should be a call to a function called process.
应该调用称为过程的函数。
I passed it, I think, maybe.
我想，我通过了它。
Nope.
没有。
Here it is, here it is, here it is.
在这里，在这里，就在这里。
Okay.
好的。
So after we go through a whole bunch of important but kind of unrelated things with respect
因此，在我们经历了一大堆重要但无关的事情之后
to inserting a block, we can finally get to this function process, which is what I wrote
要插入一个块，我们最终可以进入此功能过程，这就是我写的
in the outline originally.
在大纲中。
And this is the function that I was trying to spec out
这是我试图说明的功能
a bit for you in the overview.
在概述中为您有点。
So it takes, as you can see,
因此，如您所见，
something kind of similar to what we showed
与我们展示的类似的东西
in that overview.
在该概述中。
It's taking a block, it's taking a state DB.
它占据了一个障碍，它正在使用状态数据库。
I think I also passed the parent,
我想我也通过了父母
but we have that accessible to us.
但是我们可以访问我们。
Sorry, we don't really need that at this point
抱歉，我们真的不需要
because the parent information is put into the VM config.
因为将父信息放入VM配置中。
That's kind of like the environment for the execution.
这就像执行的环境一样。
So it's calling an interface there.
因此，它在那里调用一个接口。
I can access it in State Processor.
我可以在国家处理器中访问它。
So the actual implementation for this function is in here.
因此，此功能的实际实现在这里。
StateProcessor.go.
StateProcessor.go。
So this is where we really perform the state transition in Go Ethereum.
因此，这就是我们真正在以太坊中进行国家过渡的地方。
There's a lot more here than what we talked about in the example, but you can basically see like a very similar structure in general.
这里比我们在示例中谈论的要多得多，但是您基本上可以看到一个非常相似的结构。
So up here, we're just creating a bunch of values that we're going to maintain throughout the execution of the block.
因此，在这里，我们只是创建一堆值，这些值将在整个块的执行过程中维护。
Here's used gas.
这是二手气。
At the end, we want to make sure the gas that we used is equal to what the gas used in the header says.
最后，我们要确保我们使用的气体等于标题中使用的气体所说的气体。
This is an important check for verifying all the execution went correctly.
这是验证所有执行正确的重要检查。
And then we have our loop.
然后我们有循环。
So we just go through all the transactions in the block
因此，我们只是通过块中的所有交易
and we apply the transaction.
我们应用交易。
The apply transaction does kind of like what we talked about
申请交易确实像我们谈论的
or eventually we get here and we call the VM.
或者最终我们到达这里，我们称为VM。
We have to go through this function transition DB.
我们必须经过此功能过渡DB。
Transition DB does a bunch of the transaction level validation.
Transition DB进行了一堆事务级验证。
So it has a pre-check function.
因此它具有预检查功能。
That's verifying that the nonce of the transaction is correct.
这在验证交易的nonce是正确的。
that the balance of the transaction is correct some other like overflows that could happen um
交易的平衡是正确的
some 1559 checks a lot of the fee validation is done here and eventually
大约1559会检查很多费用验证，最终在这里完成
we verify you know there's a lot of small verifications that have to happen but
我们验证您知道，必须发生很多小的验证
But eventually we get to this point where we can execute that transaction.
但是最终，我们到达可以执行该交易的时候。
And that is, I passed it.
就是说，我通过了它。
Ah, here it is.
啊，在这里。
Okay, so here we're saying there's two types of instantiations of execution.
好的，在这里我们说执行的实例是两种类型。
Either you're executing a contract creation or you're executing a call.
要么要执行合同创建，要么要执行呼叫。
And we've sort of, we've made it so that we have these functions create and call.
而且我们已经做到了，以便我们创建和调用这些功能。
So here you can see if the transaction is going to create something,
因此，在这里您可以查看交易是否会创建某些东西，
we're going to call the create function and that does the creation.
我们将调用创建功能，并可以执行创建。
And if we're not creating, then we have to update the nonce.
而且，如果我们不是创建，那么我们必须更新NONCE。
In create, the nonce is already updated.
在创建中，NONCE已经更新。
So that's not, that doesn't exist in this branch of the code,
所以不是，这在代码的这个分支中不存在，
but we update the nonce and we then perform the call.
但是我们更新了NONCE，然后执行呼叫。
And so I'm going to skip over the implementation of call
因此，我将跳过呼叫的实施
because we'll look at that a little bit when we look at the EVM.
因为当我们查看EVM时，我们会稍微看一下。
But this is essentially kicking the EVM up
但这本质上是在踢出EVM
and saying I want to execute an EVM with this as my message sender.
并说我想用它作为我的消息发件人执行EVM。
This is the destination.
这是目的地。
So go load the code at that destination
因此，在该目的地加载代码
and then pass this data into that destination as call data.
然后将此数据作为呼叫数据传递到该目的地。
So that processes, we get a return value, we get gas remaining, which if you subtract that from the gas passed in, you get the amount of gas that was used and any errors that occurred during execution.
因此，流程，我们获得了回报值，我们将获得剩余的气体，如果您从传递的气体中减去燃气，您将获得所用的气体数量以及执行过程中发生的任何错误。
we refund some gas to the user if there were some refunds from resetting storage we pay out
如果我们支付的重置存储空间退款，我们会将一些汽油退还给用户
the coinbase the fee that was charged to the user to execute that transaction and then we
共同基础向用户收取的费用以执行该交易，然后我们
return that execution result and so if we bounce back up we're back to apply message
返回该执行结果，因此，如果我们反弹，我们又回来应用消息
which we just accumulate that gas used.
我们只是积累了使用的气体。
We accumulate this receipt into our list of receipts.
我们将此收据累积到我们的收据列表中。
Into our list of receipts there, the logs are accumulated.
进入我们那里的收据列表，日志累积了。
And eventually we go through all those transactions.
最终，我们进行了所有这些交易。
We complete this transaction loop
我们完成此交易循环
and we get to this function that I sort of mentioned before,
我们以前提到过这个功能，
finalize, which is going to just apply
最终确定，这将仅适用
some consensus specific things.
一些特定的共识。
So an interesting one that we have for the beacon chain is in finalize, we actually apply the withdrawals because this is kind of a consensus layer primitive, I guess you could say, where it really has nothing to do with the transactions.
因此，我们为信标链所拥有的一个有趣的链条即将到来，我们实际上应用了提款，因为这是一个共识层原始的，我想您可以说，这确实与交易无关。
it's all about the fact that we're running a beacon chain, a proof of stake, click, for example,
这是关于我们正在运行一个信标链的事实，例如，请单击，例如
another type of consensus that go Ethereum generally supports does not have withdrawals.
以太坊的另一种共识通常没有提款。
And so you need to have a place to differentiate it. And that's where this function finalize comes
因此，您需要有一个区分它的地方。这就是此功能最终确定的地方
into play. It lets us differentiate between different consensus engines that we might have.
发挥作用。它使我们可以区分我们可能拥有的不同共识引擎。
So finalize is going to go through each of the withdrawals that happen from the beacon chain,
因此，最终确定将经历从信标连锁店发生的每个提款
that the beacon chain told us what happened
信标连锁告诉我们发生了什么
in this block, and it just performs them.
在这个块中，它只是执行它们。
So it adds a balance out of thin air.
因此，它增加了稀薄的空气。
It's basically just taking some ether
基本上只是服用一些以太
that was on that beacon chain
那是在那个灯塔链上
and putting it onto the execution layer.
并将其放在执行层上。
So once that's all done, once that's finalized,
因此，一旦完成了，一旦完成，
we can return our receipts.
我们可以退还收据。
Let's see if I can bounce back to where this is called.
让我们看看我是否可以反弹回到所谓的位置。
so we were digging into this function
所以我们正在研究这个功能
apply transaction
应用交易
all those transactions
所有这些交易
oh sorry we were digging into process
哦，对不起，我们正在研究过程
so once process is done
所以一旦完成
we are in blockchain
我们在区块链中
and now the blockchain is basically
现在，区块链基本上是
processed that
处理了
so it's going to do some more things
所以它将做更多的事情
update some metrics
更新一些指标
and eventually we're going to write that block to state
最终我们将写那个块
and this is kind of
这是一种
when everything is resolved onto the disk or into your memory.
当一切都解决到磁盘或内存中时。
So at this point, we are inserting the block.
因此，在这一点上，我们正在插入块。
The block was valid.
块是有效的。
And there's just some more metrics and small things that we do.
而且我们还有更多的指标和小事。
But basically, at the end, we return the number of blocks
但基本上，最后，我们返回块数
that were written to the disk.
写在磁盘上。
And we return if there were any errors.
如果有任何错误，我们返回。
since there would have been no errors, we successfully wrote that block, we would just say,
由于没有错误，我们成功地写了这个障碍，我们只是说，
in this case, one block was written. And if we go all the way back to the Catalyst API,
在这种情况下，写了一个块。如果我们一直回到催化剂API，
so this actually throws away the number of blocks that were written, it just checks to see if error,
因此，这实际上扔掉了写的块数，它只是检查是否错误，
there was no error, we would get the error nil error back from insert block without set head,
没有错误，我们会在没有设置头的情况下从插入块中恢复错误零错误，
skip through all of this uh and eventually we would return a payload status status engine valid
跳过所有这些UH，最终我们将返回有效载荷状态状态引擎有效
and a new latest hash which is the block that was just inserted so that's the full block insertion
还有一个新的最新哈希，这是刚刚插入的块，这就是完整的块插入
pipeline that happens whenever a consensus layer gets a block and it sends it to the execution
每当共识层得到一个块并将其发送到执行时，就会发生的管道
layer i know that was a lot i don't want to get hung up on like a whole bunch of questions but
我知道这是很多我不想像一堆问题一样挂断的，但是
if there are some like high level things that i could answer quickly before we talk about some
如果有一些像高水平的事情，我可以在谈论一些之前很快回答
other stuff, I am open to that.
其他东西，我对此很开放。
Thank you so much.
太感谢了。
We have it on higher level.
我们将其具有更高的水平。
If you can explain again what a receipt is.
如果您可以再次解释什么是收据。
Yeah.
是的。
So a receipt is information about a transaction that can only be verified or determined after
因此收据是有关交易的信息，该信息只能在
executing the transaction so if we look at the consensus definition of a receipt it has things
执行交易，因此，如果我们查看收据的共识定义，则有东西
like so these are the consensus fields these are the things that are actually in a receipt this
就像这些是共识字段，这些是实际上收据中的东西
other stuff is some go ethereum stuff that's not in the receipt but you have things such as the type
其他东西是一些没有收据中的以太坊东西，但是您有类型的东西
which says that you know what transaction type this receipt was associated with
说您知道此收据与
And that's used as a discriminator, basically, so you can interpret if different types of transactions have different types of different types of receipts, which I don't think they really do at the moment.
基本上，这被用作歧视者，因此您可以解释不同类型的交易是否具有不同类型的不同类型的收据，我认为他们目前并不是这样。
Post state, this was deprecated in Byzantium, I think, but it's been deprecated for quite a while.
我认为，在州后，这是在拜占庭的，但已被贬低了一段时间。
So really what you have are these, you have status, which would say whether or not a transaction
因此，您确实拥有这些，您有状态，这将说明是否交易
reverted, you would have gas, cumulative gas used, which says how much gas that transaction
恢复，您将使用汽油，累积气体，这说明了该交易多少
used the Bloom filter.
使用了Bloom过滤器。
I would, if you're not familiar with what Bloom filters are, I would check that out
我会，如果您不熟悉Bloom过滤器是什么，我会检查一下
on Wikipedia.
在维基百科。
It's basically a fast way to determine if it's possible, a log you're looking for occurred
基本上，这是确定是否可能的快速方法，您正在寻找的日志发生
within that transaction.
在该交易中。
And then you just have a list of all the logs and a log is something that you can write
然后，您只有所有日志的列表，并且您可以编写日志
from a smart contract, the smart contract address would be here. And you can have topics which help
从智能合同中，智能合约地址将在这里。而且您可以有帮助的主题
you quickly find it via the Bloom filter. And then you have the data. So an example of a log might be
您可以通过Bloom过滤器快速找到它。然后您有数据。所以一个日志的示例可能是
if you send an ERC-20, that ERC-20 might set out a log that says some amount of that ERC-20 was sent
如果您发送ERC-20，ERC-20可能会列出一个日志，该日志显示了一定的ERC-20已发送
from one address to another address. And so you could read that from the block at the end of the
从一个地址到另一个地址。因此，您可以从末端的块中读取
transaction and see all of the ERC-20 transfers that happened with a particular token.
交易并查看特定令牌发生的所有ERC-20转移。
Awesome. Thanks a lot, Matt. One more question is about environment of multiple
惊人的。非常感谢，马特。另一个问题是关于多个的环境
transactions which result in multiple other transactions, like contracts calling other
导致多项其他交易的交易，例如致电其他交易
contracts, et cetera. How is the context, the environment that you used in your overview,
合同等。您在概述中使用的上下文，如何
variable how is it how it's fetched okay let me see if I can show this really quickly I want to
变量如何获取它，好的，让我看看我是否可以非常快速地显示我想
go to state processor so there's two kind of environments that we care about there I think
去国有处理器，所以我们认为有两种环境
think this is the right one so we got have the evm environment which stores mostly transaction
认为这是合适的
level context and block level context so block level are things that i mentioned coinbase gas
级别上下文和块级别上下文，因此块级别是我提到的coinbase as gas
limit block number time difficulty base fee random all this stuff this is stuff that doesn't change
限制块编号时间难度基本费用随机所有这些东西，这是不变的东西
transaction to transaction it's fixed across the entire block then we have transaction context
交易交易已固定在整个块上，然后我们有交易上下文
origin, gas price, blob stuff.
起源，汽油价格，斑点的东西。
These are things that are true across the whole transaction,
这些都是整个交易中真实的事情，
but might change within the block
但是可能在块内发生变化
because there are different transactions.
因为有不同的交易。
So these are two types of environments
因此，这是两种类型的环境
which are accessible during execution,
在执行过程中可以访问
but are generally fixed for the full execution of the transaction.
但通常是为交易的全部执行而修复。
Then there's also in the interpreter,
然后在口译员中也有
an EVO, no, is that right?
evo，不，是吗？
Okay, so inside the interpreter, you have some things.
好的，在口译员内，您有一些东西。
And you have, for one, the scope context,
而且，您有一个范围上下文
which we'll look at here in just a second,
我们将在此处浏览一下，
that has things related to the current scope that you're in.
这与您所处的当前范围有关。
So if you are accessing the stack in the current scope
因此，如果您要访问当前范围中的堆栈
or the memory in the current scope
或当前范围中的内存
or storage via contract in the current scope.
或通过当前范围中的合同存储。
Those are all things that are accessible,
这些都是可以访问的东西，
that change within that transaction frame to frame.
该交易框架内的变化。
Every time you invoke something that adds a new call frame,
每当您调用一些添加新呼叫框架的东西时，
things like call, delegate call, create, create to,
诸如呼叫，委托呼叫，创建，创建诸如
that's going to create new scopes.
这将创建新的范围。
And then contract is also an interesting one
然后合同也是一个有趣的合同
because it has the sender in it.
因为它有发件人。
So the caller here is the message.sender if you write some solidity.
因此，呼叫者是消息。Sender如果您写一些坚固性。
So this is an environment context that's changing within the transaction.
因此，这是在交易中发生变化的环境环境。
And this is what the EVM, the interpreter, will use to fill requests for instructions.
这就是EVM（解释器）将用来填写指令请求。
Like, what's the caller?
就像，呼叫者是什么？
Who called this contract?
谁称这份合同？
Or what's the value of this piece of memory right here?
或者在这里这段记忆的价值是什么？
These are things that are accessible via this environment variable.
这些是可以通过此环境变量访问的东西。
So I was kind of simplifying a lot of that stuff, but
所以我有点简化了很多东西，但是
that's how it looks if you start to dig in,
如果您开始挖掘出来，它就是这样，
in the actual implementation here in the VM that we have.
在我们拥有的VM中的实际实现中。
Awesome, thanks for diving there.
太棒了，感谢您在那里潜水。
I've been seeing new questions, but people are still typing,
我一直在看到新问题，但是人们仍在打字，
there's a slight delay with the screen, so-
屏幕有轻微的延迟，所以 -
Okay. Well, let's keep going then.
好的。好吧，让我们继续前进。
I've got a couple other things to talk about before we close up.
在我们关闭之前，我还有其他几件事要谈论。
So that was the state transition function.
这就是状态过渡函数。
Let's dig in even deeper and talk about what the Ethereum virtual machine is.
让我们更深入地研究以太坊虚拟机是什么。
So to illustrate this, I want to make a quick diagram.
因此，为了说明这一点，我想快速图表。
so that you can have an idea of what is going on within the EVM.
这样您就可以了解EVM内部发生的事情。
I think I sort of just showed quite a bit of stuff
我想我只是展示了很多东西
about the different contexts that exist within the EVM,
关于EVM中存在的不同上下文，
but I tend to find that people understand it a bit better
但是我倾向于发现人们更好地理解它
if they have a picture to look at.
如果他们有图片要看。
So we'll call this the EVM.
因此，我们将其称为EVM。
This is the EVM box.
这是EVM框。
And this is essentially an EVM call frame.
这本质上是EVM呼叫框架。
And so like I was saying, the call frame changes throughout the transaction, and you have access only to things that are related to that call frame.
因此，就像我说的那样，呼叫框架在整个交易中都会发生变化，并且您只能访问与该呼叫框架相关的事物。
So a big example of what's accessible in that call frame is the code.
因此，该呼叫框架中可访问的内容是代码。
This is the code that you are currently executing.
这是您当前正在执行的代码。
And alongside that code, you need to know where in the code you're executing.
除了该代码外，您还需要知道要执行的代码中的位置。
So you have the PC, that's the program counter.
因此，您有PC，这是程序计数器。
if you're familiar with with interpreters at all then you will be familiar with how the pc works
如果您完全熟悉口译员，那么您将熟悉PC的工作原理
but basically it's just saying uh the way the interpreter is processing this is if pc is at
但基本上只是在说解释器处理的方式是PC在
zero it would load the instruction at index zero in the code and then execute it and then it would
为零，它将将指令加载为代码中的索引零，然后执行该指令，然后将其加载
update the pc by one or possibly more if the instruction uh was larger than one byte but
如果指令大于一个字节，则更新PC或可能更多的PC
Most of our instructions are one byte.
我们的大多数说明都是一个字节。
So then we have some other frame level stuff.
因此，我们还有其他一些框架级别的东西。
We have the stack, we have the memory,
我们有堆栈，我们有记忆，
we have the gas remaining.
我们还剩下气体。
And these are mostly the things that we have
这些主要是我们拥有的东西
with respect to just this frame of execution.
关于这种执行框架。
We also have things like we saw,
我们也有像我们看到的东西
we have the block context that I just went over
我们有我刚刚过去的块上下文
and we have the Tx context.
我们有TX上下文。
These are accessible within the frame.
这些在框架内可访问。
We also have the state which is accessible.
我们也有可访问的状态。
So there's a bunch of operations
所以有很多操作
that can access parts of the state.
可以访问该州的一部分。
Things like xcode-size xcode-hash,
XCode-Size Xcode-Hash之类的东西，
meaning external code size or external code hash.
意思是外部代码大小或外部代码哈希。
Those are instructions that would let you read things from the state.
这些是可以让您阅读州的内容的说明。
Instructions like Coinbase give you block context.
诸如Coinbase之类的说明为您提供块上下文。
Instructions like Origin give you transaction context.
诸如Origin之类的说明为您提供交易上下文。
Okay, this is mostly what the VM looks like.
好的，这主要是VM的样子。
To understand a bit more about how the EVM works,
要了解有关EVM的工作原理的更多信息，
we can have a quick example program.
我们可以有一个快速示例程序。
And we'll do it on this playground here.
我们将在这里的操场上做。
Oh, they already have one.
哦，他们已经有一个。
Yeah, let's just use this one.
是的，让我们使用这个。
So the way the stack machine works is
因此，堆栈机的工作方式是
the stack is kind of your working place for doing operations.
堆栈是您进行操作的工作场所。
All the instructions essentially take stack arguments
所有说明本质上都采用堆栈论点
to modify the behavior of that specific instruction.
修改该特定指令的行为。
So in this example, essentially, we're writing something to the memory with mStore, and then we're going to return it to the caller.
因此，在此示例中，本质上，我们正在用Mstore写一些内容，然后我们将其归还给呼叫者。
So if we look at how that looks, if we step by step, we're on this first instruction.
因此，如果我们看一下看起来，如果我们逐步逐步，我们将使用第一个指令。
So if we're thinking about this picture here, PC is equal to zero.
因此，如果我们在这里考虑这张照片，PC等于零。
So in this example, we would have our PC at zero.
因此，在此示例中，我们的PC为零。
Our stack and our memory are empty.
我们的堆栈和记忆是空的。
and then gas remaining is kind of irrelevant,
然后剩余的气体无关紧要，
but let's just imagine we have basically infinite gas remaining.
但是，让我们想象我们基本上还有无限的气体。
If we step one through, we've pushed a value on,
如果我们一步一步，我们已经推动了一个价值，
and that value is 42.
该值是42。
So now our stack has grown to one element,
所以现在我们的堆栈已经成长为一个元素，
and it has the value 42 on top.
它的值为42。
We run another instruction, again, push one.
我们再次运行另一项指令，推一个。
That's pushing zero onto the stack.
这将零推到堆栈上。
And now we're at mStore.
现在我们在Mstore。
So mStore, the way that mStore works is it takes
因此，Mstore的工作方式是
the first element on the stack it uses that as the offset to write a value and then it reads the
堆栈上的第一个元素使用该元素作为编写值的偏移，然后读取
next item on the stack and it writes that value to that offset so when I press this next button
堆栈上的下一个项目，它将该值写入该偏移量，因此当我按下下一个按钮时
what's going to happen is we're going to remove both of the stack elements but then the memory
会发生的事情是，我们将删除两个堆栈元素，然后再进行内存
is going to have 42 written to it and that's exactly what happened here so now we want to
要写42个，这正是这里发生的事情，所以现在我们想
return this value so the way to return a value is you need to say how big the return value is going
返回此值，因此返回值的方式是您需要说退货值有多大
to be. And you need to say where to start reading that return value. And the way that it does that
是。您需要说从哪里开始阅读该回报值。以及这样做的方式
here is we push the hex value 20, which is 32 in decimal. And then we push the index to start with,
这是我们推动十六进制值20，即十进制为32。然后我们将索引从开始，
which is zero. So we're going to start here. And we'll pass in all 32 of these bytes. So if we just
是零。因此，我们将从这里开始。我们将通过所有这些字节中的所有32个。所以，如果我们只是
look at those, we push 20 onto the stack and the zero onto the stack. And then we pop them both
看看这些，我们将20个将堆放到堆上，然后将零推到堆栈上。然后我们将他们俩弹出
off with return. And so now we get this return value of 42. And that is like really roughly how
退货。因此，现在我们获得了42个回报值。这真的很粗略
a stack machine works, how to think about the behavior within the EVM. I will mention that
堆栈机有效，如何思考EVM内的行为。我会提到
within the EVM, there's a bunch of different types of instructions. What we looked at there
在EVM中，有许多不同类型的说明。我们在那里看的东西
are some pretty simple stuff. In general, you can think of the different categories.
是一些非常简单的东西。通常，您可以想到不同的类别。
is this things like arithmetic.
这是算术之类的东西吗？
So arithmetic is adding, subtracting, exponentiation,
因此，算术正在增加，减法，凸起，
doing modulos, that type of stuff.
做模特，这种类型的东西。
There's bitwise functions for bitbanging.
有位函数用于位弯曲。
If you need to do an and, an x or a not,
如果您需要做一个X或AN，则
those functions exist.
这些功能存在。
There are environment functions,
有环境功能，
which give us this access to the block context
这使我们可以访问块上下文
and the TX context, like I mentioned.
就像我提到的那样，TX上下文。
And shoot.
并射击。
We also have call frame instructions.
我们还具有呼叫框架说明。
We saw that a little bit whenever we were looking at the transition DB method where
每当我们查看过渡数据库方法时，我们都会看到一点
upon a create, we call evm.create upon a call, we call evm.call.
创建时，我们致电EVM.在电话时致电，我们致电EVM.Call。
These are all in types of instructions that also exist in the EVM.
这些都是EVM中也存在的指令类型。
if you need to create a new call frame,
如果您需要创建一个新的呼叫框架，
there's control flow.
有控制流。
So if you wanna have more complicated programs,
因此，如果您想拥有更复杂的程序，
programs that branch,
分支的程序，
and by branching, maybe an example I can show is,
通过分支，也许我可以显示的一个例子是，
is this 4788 contract.
这是4788合同。
So there's a night, so this is the contract for 4788,
所以有一个晚上，所以这是4788的合同，
which is going to be used in the next hard fork,
这将在下一个硬叉中使用，
But you can see an example of branching here.
但是您可以在这里看到一个分支的示例。
So what this is doing is it's going to branch
所以这是要分支机构的
depending on if the caller is equal to this big number,
根据呼叫者是否等于这个大数字，
which this number is a special number.
这个数字是一个特殊的数字。
It's the system address.
这是系统地址。
And this is how 4788 works.
这就是4788的工作方式。
The system will call this contract with this address.
该系统将使用此地址调用此合同。
And in that case, we know this is a special call.
在这种情况下，我们知道这是一个特别的电话。
So we use jump I to determine
因此，我们使用跳跃i来确定
if the equal of caller and that number is true,
如果呼叫者的平等和该号码为真，
we would jump to a certain value.
我们会跳到一定的价值。
And if it's not, we would jump to a different value.
如果不是这样，我们将跳到不同的价值。
So that's something that allows you
这就是让你的
to control the flow of the program.
控制程序的流程。
And then there's also stack ops.
然后还有堆栈操作。
So we saw some stack ops in that example.
因此，我们在该示例中看到了一些堆栈操作。
There was push.
有推动。
There's also things like pop and swap.
还有流行和交换之类的东西。
so that lets you just manipulate the stack in different ways
这样就可以让您以不同的方式操纵堆栈
and then there's some system types of calls
然后有一些系统类型的调用
which I guess I can put the
我想我可以把
we can say call as part of the system calls
我们可以说呼叫作为系统呼叫的一部分
so we can say call create
所以我们可以说呼叫创建
we saw this return value that's type of system call
我们看到了这种返回值的系统调用类型
yeah
是的
maybe store
也许是商店
This writes to the storage of the contract.
这写信给合同的存储。
And then there's some memory operations.
然后有一些内存操作。
We can do mload, mstore, mstore8,
我们可以进行MLOAD，MSTORE，MSTORE8，
which stores one single byte.
存储一个单个字节。
So these are things that let us manipulate the memory
因此，这些是让我们操纵记忆的事情
within the frame.
在框架内。
Okay, that was a super fast crash course
好吧，那是一个超级快速的速成课程
on EVM-related things.
在与EVM相关的事物上。
Any questions on EVM?
关于EVM有什么疑问吗？
uh one question from paul uh asking how were various instruction costs determined
嗯，保罗·UH问一个问题，询问如何确定各种教学成本
uh a long time ago there was
嗯，很久以前有
there was some benchmarking done i forget what the target gas per second was that
做了一些基准测试，我忘记了目标气的目标是什么
we were roughly targeting i don't know if i could find i don't know if i could find that quickly
我们大概是针对的，我不知道我是否能找到我是否能很快找到
uh basically there was a gas per second that we wanted to be processed on a specific
嗯，基本上有每秒的气，我们想在特定上处理
processor architecture and that was sort of where we roughly came to the different gas prices
处理器架构，这是我们大致达到不同汽油价格的地方
and I don't remember what that gas per second off the top of my head was but we would just come up
而且我不记得我头顶上每秒的气是什么，但我们会出现
with a benchmark that used the instruction and we would run that many many times to sort of see how
使用使用该指令的基准测试，我们将多次运行
many times you could run that per second and then work backwards to figure out what is the
很多时候您可以每秒运行，然后向后工作以找出什么是
appropriate like you know if this instruction takes so long then what gas would we need to
像您知道此指令是否需要这么长时间，那么我们需要什么气
get to that gas per second value. At this point, you know, we have a lot of instructions. And so
每秒钟到达该气体。在这一点上，您知道，我们有很多说明。所以
sometimes we don't super closely do this type of benchmarking. So base fee came with the London
有时我们不会超级执行这种类型的基准测试。所以伦敦带来了基本费用
hard fork, and there wasn't really benchmarking done on that specific instruction, because we
坚硬的叉子，在该特定指令上并没有真正的基准测试，因为我们
just copied the same gas value that is charged for other block context types of instructions.
只是复制了与其他块上下文类型指令相同的气值。
So a lot of these things today just use what the gas cost of other similar types of instructions are.
因此，如今许多这些事情只需使用其他类似类型的说明的气体成本即可。
We still have this rough gas per second that we want to process, but I don't think that things are perfectly in line.
我们仍然要处理这种粗糙的气体，但我认为事情并不是一条完美的。
I think that some things are probably being overcharged for.
我认为某些事情可能会被过多收费。
awesome thank you
太好了，谢谢
few people
很少有人
typing right now so maybe we'll give
现在打字，所以也许我们会给
five seconds and
五秒钟
if something comes up we can
如果有什么事，我们可以
continue here
继续这里
yeah I have like maybe 15 more minutes
是的，我还有15分钟
or so of stuff I don't know if that's okay
大概是我不知道这是否还可以的
yeah
是的
it's great
这很棒
sweet
甜的
cool let's
酷让我们
just keep moseying on and then we can do
只要继续努力，然后我们就可以做
a big session of questions at the end.
最后一个问题。
Okay.
好的。
All right, we talked about block validation.
好吧，我们谈到了块验证。
We talked about block building,
我们谈论了建筑物，
the state transition function,
状态过渡函数，
super high-level overview about how the EVM works.
超级高级概述有关EVM的工作原理。
And now I want to talk about the peer-to-peer layer,
现在我想谈论点对点层，
which we alluded to a bit
我们提到了一点
when we were talking about the transaction pool
当我们谈论交易池
and how blocks are being built.
以及如何构建块。
But I wanted to dig in more
但是我想挖掘更多
about how does the peer-to-peer layer look,
关于点对点的外观如何，
what is its responsibilities.
它的责任是什么。
So the execution layer operates
因此执行层运行
on a P2P protocol called devP2P.
在称为DEVP2P的P2P协议上。
And devP2P is something that is a bespoke protocol for Ethereum.
DevP2P是以太坊的定制协议。
it's evolved from the beginning of Ethereum
它从以太坊的开始就发展了
a funny easter egg I guess about
我猜是一个有趣的复活节彩蛋
devP2P today
DEVP2P今天
if you're not familiar
如果你不熟悉
we call devP2P protocols
我们调用DEVP2P协议
like ETH68
像Eth68
ETH69
Eth69
I think we're on ETH68 right now
我认为我们现在正在使用Eth68
working on ETH69
在Eth69上工作
but
但
and
和
I guess I should say that this is like a sub
我想我应该说这就像一个潜艇
capability
能力
So there are other protocols under dev P2P.
因此，Dev P2P下还有其他协议。
We have ETH, we have Snap.
我们有ETH，我们有快照。
Those are the main ones today.
这些是今天的主要人物。
There used to be things like Whisper.
曾经有诸如耳语之类的东西。
um were there any other ones that i can think of i guess we can just look at it
嗯，还有其他我能想到的，我想我们可以看一下
oh yeah les
哦，是的，莱斯
yes there's some ideas for a witness propagation sub capability which would allow us to propagate
是的，有一些关于证人传播副能力的想法，这将使我们能够传播
block witnesses those are those are things yeah whisper leas s witness things are that have kind
障碍的目击者就是那些东西是的，是的，耳语le leas的见证人很友善
of been deprecated today we really just focus on on eth and snap i was going to say the funny
今天被贬低了
easter egg for eth is that you know now we're on eth 68 69 we don't we haven't had 68 eth protocols
ETH的复活节彩蛋是，您知道我们现在使用ETH 68 69我们没有68个ETH协议
i guess what happened in the early days is we started with eth 1 and then we went to eth 2
我想早期发生了什么是我们从ETH 1开始，然后我们去了ETH 2
and there's a lot of very quick iteration the very early days of ethereum and we kind of got
以太坊的早期，有很多非常快的迭代，我们有点
somewhere around eth6 and at that point they just decide i think that they started trying
在Eth6附近的某个地方，那时他们只是决定我认为他们开始尝试
to think like in terms of eth6.1 eth6.2 and all these these protocols are lost you won't really
像Eth6.1 Eth6.2一样思考，所有这些协议都丢失了，您不会真正
find these types of protocols in the in client definitions anymore because this was you know
在客户端定义中找到这些类型的协议，因为这是您知道的
pre-launch uh very early launch and so we eventually got i don't know what the
启动前的UH非常早就发布了，所以我们最终得到了我不知道什么
first one that's even mentioned here is it might be what uh
首先在这里提到的是嗯
okay so the current version is e68
好的，因此当前版本是E68
okay so yeah you 60 so we had a bunch of POC so there was like POC 1 2 3 4 5 6 and then finally
好吧，是的，您60，所以我们有一堆POC，所以有POC 1 2 3 4 5 6，然后终于
for 6 for at 6 they said we can't keep going like this let's just do 6.0 6.1 etc and so 2015 we had
他们说的是6，他们说我们不能继续这样做，让我们只做6.0 6.1等，所以2015年我们有
ith 61 uh ith 62 63 i think 64 is probably the last one you might see in clients uh but yeah
ITH 61 UH ITH 62 63我认为64可能是您在客户中可能看到的最后一个，但是是的
we've we've made a lot of different changes to these protocol so there haven't been 68
我们对这些协议进行了许多不同的更改，因此没有68
youth protocols there's been about 15 protocols which is kind of funny but okay back to what does
青年协议有大约15个协议，这很有趣，但可以回到什么
the PDP do for us? So the responsibility, we need to be able to access historical data.
PDP为我们做吗？因此，我们需要能够访问历史数据的责任。
We also need to be able to access transactions.
我们还需要能够访问交易。
I'll say new transactions actually pooled transactions. So these are pending. So these
我会说新的交易实际上汇总了交易。所以这些正在待处理。所以这些
are transactions that are trying to propagate to get into a block, they're not yet in a block,
是试图传播以进入一个块的交易，它们尚未在一个街区中，
and then state. So this is the three main pieces that the ETH protocol, the devP2P protocol,
然后说。因此，这是ETH协议DevP2P协议的三个主要部分，
the ETH protocol are trying to give to us. So let's look at accessing historical data.
ETH协议试图给我们。因此，让我们看访问历史数据。
That's done with two different methods, more or less, get headers, get block headers,
这是通过两种不同的方法完成的，或多或少，获取标题，获取块标题，
and get block bodies.
并获得块尸体。
If you think about what is historical data,
如果您考虑什么是历史数据，
it is more or less these two things.
这两件事或多或少。
There's also,
还有，
let me make sure I have this one right.
让我确保我有一个正确的。
Get block, get receipts.
获取块，获取收据。
Yeah.
是的。
So then there's also get receipts.
因此，也有收据。
So there's these three methods
所以这三种方法
that allow us to get all the historical data
这使我们能够获取所有历史数据
related to Ethereum.
与以太坊有关。
If you think about what historical data is,
如果您考虑什么是历史数据，
it's data that's not needed
这是不需要的数据
for active validation of the state transition function.
用于积极验证状态过渡函数。
And if we look back and we think
如果我们回头，我们认为
what that state transition function was,
该状态过渡功能是什么，
it's taking the parent block,
它正在带父块，
which we'll just assume is available in the client.
我们只是假设客户可以在客户端可用。
It's kind of accessible in the hot memory of the client.
在客户端的热门内存中可以访问。
the current block that we're trying to validate, and then the state. So there's no point where
我们试图验证的当前块，然后是状态。所以没有意义
it's like, let me access all of the historical blocks of Ethereum, or, you know, in the state
就像，让我访问以太坊的所有历史街区，或者，在该州
transition function, there's no place where I'm checking the header of a block from 200 blocks
过渡功能，我没有地方检查200个块的街区的标题
ago. So that's why we refer to this as historical data, things that happened in the chain,
前。因此，这就是为什么我们将其称为历史数据，链中发生的事情，
but not necessarily in the active path for validation.
但不一定要在验证的活动路径中。
We also have some methods for getting transactions.
我们也有一些获得交易的方法。
We have the method transactions, which has existed for quite a while.
我们有方法交易，已经存在了一段时间。
And then we have this newer method called new pooled transaction hashes.
然后，我们有了一种新的方法，称为新的合并交易哈希。
And this new pooled transaction hashes method came along, I think in ETH 66.
我认为，这种新的汇总交易哈希方法出现在66中。
and the rationale at that time was that we needed to reduce the bandwidth usage of an execution
当时的理由是我们需要减少执行的带宽使用
client and even you know even today especially today now that once your client is synced
客户，甚至您甚至今天都知道，尤其是今天，一旦您的客户同步
most of your pretty much all of your transaction or sorry all of your network bandwidth is going
您几乎所有的交易或对不起的所有网络带宽都在进行
towards transactions and so in e66 peter wanted to figure out a way to reduce the load the bandwidth
迈向交易，因此在E66中，彼得想找出一种减少带宽负载的方法
load for execution clients and it came up with an idea that instead of sending the full transaction
执行客户的加载，并提出了一个想法，即不是发送完整的交易
to every single one of our peers when we get a new transaction either a peer announces that
当我们获得新的交易时，每一个同行都宣布
transaction to us or we receive it locally instead of sending that to all of our peers
交易给我们，或者我们在本地收到，而不是将其发送给我们的所有同行
we will only send this to a square rooted peers and all the rest of our peers would receive
我们只会将其发送到一个平方根的同伴，我们所有的其他同龄人都会收到
new pool transactions.
新的池交易。
And the full transactions goes to
完整的交易是
a random subset, a random
随机子集，随机子集
subset of square root peers.
平方根对等的子集。
And so this really helped mitigate
因此，这确实有助于减轻
the bandwidth usage
带宽的用法
where I'm getting the same transaction
我得到同样的交易的地方
over and over again from many different
一遍又一遍地与许多不同
nodes.
节点。
Now I get mostly
现在我大部分
just duplicate hashes from other nodes.
只需重复其他节点的哈希。
And I'll only call this method
而且我只称呼此方法
I think it's
我认为是
get pooled transaction.
获得汇总交易。
So I'll only call this method get pooled transactions
因此，我只称此方法得到汇总的交易
if I receive some hashes that I haven't seen before.
如果我收到一些以前从未见过的哈希。
One interesting thing we can look at
我们可以看的一件有趣的事情
is we can actually go and see exactly the line of code
我们实际上可以去准确查看代码线吗
where Ethereum does the square root announcement.
以太坊进行平方根公告的地方。
That's in ETH.
那是在eth中。
I think it's in handler.
我认为这是在处理者中。
So there's a function broadcast transactions.
因此，有一个功能广播交易。
This method is called whenever there are transactions that can be broadcast.
只要有可以广播的交易，该方法就会称为。
What it does is it...
它的作用是...
Okay, so for every transaction, we determine if that transaction has been seen by that
好的，所以对于每笔交易，我们确定该交易是否已通过该交易
other client, and we also determine how many of our peers are going to receive this directly,
其他客户，我们还确定我们有多少同龄人将直接接收到这一点，
and there that square root function is.
正方形的根函数是。
So depending on how many peers we have, we take the square root of that, and that is
因此，根据我们有多少同龄人，我们将其占据平方根，也就是说
the number of direct peers. Where do we use that? Yeah, okay. So I think peers is a random
直接同行的数量。我们在哪里使用？是的，好吧。所以我认为同龄人是一个随机的
list of our peers. And so here we say, okay, all the way up into num direct. So you can imagine
同行名单。因此，我们在这里说，好吧，一直到Num Direct。所以你可以想象
This is a small value, say two.
这是一个很小的价值，说两个。
So peers index zero and one,
所以同行索引零，一个，
we will send this transaction unconditionally.
我们将无条件发送此交易。
And for everyone else,
对于其他所有人，
we're just using list slicing here.
我们只是在这里使用列表切片。
We're going to send all the rest of our peers
我们将发送所有其他同龄人
just an announcement.
只是一个公告。
So that's using this announcement list
这就是使用此公告清单
versus the TX set list.
与TX集列表相比。
So that's in this file, what is it?
这就是在这个文件中，这是什么？
eth slash handler.go.
Eth Slash Handler.go。
You can actually see this is where this behavior
您实际上可以看到这是这种行为的地方
from the dev P2P layer is coming through.
从开发人员中，P2P层即将到来。
So if we look quickly at the different methods,
因此，如果我们快速查看不同的方法，
let's look at each of them.
让我们看一下它们。
Git block headers.
GIT块标题。
The requests, we use this request ID.
请求，我们使用此请求ID。
this was added in maybe ETH 67
这也许是在eth 67中添加的
and the request ID
和请求ID
just lets us keep track of our requests a bit better
只是让我们更好地跟踪我们的要求
so when we send a request
因此，当我们发送请求时
we send an ID
我们发送ID
and then the response comes back
然后回应又回来了
and it gives us the same ID
它给了我们相同的ID
just helps with tracking requests
只是帮助跟踪请求
tracking requests that are in flight
跟踪飞行中的请求
and we say here's a start block
我们说这是一个开始
so this would be the block value
所以这将是块值
that we would want to start receiving from,
我们想开始从
and we would say how many blocks we would want,
我们会说我们想要多少个街区，
and then we have the ability
然后我们有能力
to also get them potentially in reverse.
还可以使它们有可能相反。
And this is important because before the merge,
这很重要，因为在合并之前，
the way that you would sync a node,
您同步节点的方式，
sync the history,
同步历史，
is you would start from Genesis
你会从创世纪开始吗
because this was the first place
因为这是第一个
where this is the trusted root of the chain,
这是链的可信根，
and we would just sync forward.
我们只会同步。
We would download all of the headers,
我们将下载所有标题，
download all the block bodies.
下载所有块尸体。
And so we would be syncing,
因此，我们将同步
we would be saying start blocks zero,
我们会说开始块零，
download 20 blocks in order from zero.
从零下载20个块。
So then we would get to 20.
因此，我们将达到20。
With the merge, we actually sync in reverse.
通过合并，我们实际上是相反的。
So we have a trusted checkpoint,
因此，我们有一个值得信赖的检查站，
which is a little bit like the Genesis.
有点像创世纪。
But now that the trusted checkpoint is somewhere,
但是现在值得信赖的检查站在某个地方，
you know, non-zero portion of the chain past Genesis,
您知道，链的非零部分过去的创世纪，
us, we want to get the historical data.
我们，我们想获取历史数据。
So if our checkpoint is like block
因此，如果我们的检查点就像块
n, we would then
n，我们会
say I want to get
说我想得到
starting block at n, limit of
n处的起始块，极限
maybe 20, and get the blocks in
也许20，然后将街区放入
reverse. And so we would download
撤销。所以我们会下载
n-1, n-2, all the
N-1，N-2，所有
way to n-20. And so
到达N-20的方式。所以
that would let us go backwards and download all of
那会让我们向后下载
those blocks.
那些块。
Basically, same thing for
基本上，同一件事
getBlockBodies.
GetBlockbodies。
Once we
曾经
actually, no, this one is a bit different.
实际上，不，这个有些不同。
So if we've already gotten the headers,
因此，如果我们已经获得了标题，
once we've already gotten the headers,
一旦我们已经获得了标题，
we know what the block hashes are.
我们知道块是什么。
So we can just ask for the bodies
所以我们可以要求尸体
related to those specific headers.
与那些特定的标题有关。
So we would send a list of all the block hashes that we have
因此，我们将发送我们拥有的所有块哈希的列表
and get the bodies for those.
并为那些尸体。
And I'm getting receipts is the same as that.
而且我得到的收据与那相同。
Yeah, so in the same deal with receipts,
是的，在收据同样的交易中，
we have our chain,
我们有我们的链
we've received our chain via get block header.
我们通过GET Block标头收到了链条。
And then we just go and we get all those receipts
然后我们去，我们得到所有这些收据
by asking for the receipts by the block hash.
通过要求块哈希收据。
So that's getting the historical data for pending transactions.
因此，这是获取待处理交易的历史数据。
We have a method.
我们有一种方法。
Transactions.
交易。
And so this can come without any kind of request associated with it.
因此，这可能没有任何类型的请求。
A lot of the other messages are get block, get transaction, whatever.
许多其他消息是获取块，获得交易等等。
This one is something you would just send unconditionally to your peer,
这是您只会无条件发送给同伴的东西，
like we saw in broadcast functions broadcast transactions,
就像我们在广播功能中看到的广播交易一样，
this will directly send the transactions immediately to your peer.
这将直接将交易直接发送到您的同伴。
And so it's really just sending a list of transactions.
因此，它实际上只是发送交易列表。
The other one is the new pool transaction hashes.
另一个是新的池交易哈希。
This one is a bit more complicated,
这个更复杂，
but basically it's just sending a list of the transaction types,
但基本上只是发送交易类型的列表，
their sizes, and the hashes of the transactions.
它们的大小以及交易的哈希。
So once you receive that, you can see if these are transaction hashes that you haven't seen before.
因此，一旦收到了这些，您就可以查看这些是您以前从未见过的交易哈希。
If they are transaction hashes that you have not seen before, you can call get pool transactions, pass it the transaction hashes, and then the peer will respond with the full transaction values.
如果它们是您以前从未见过的交易哈希，则可以调用获取池交易，将其传递给事务哈希，然后同行将以完整的事务值响应。
And that comes back in pool transactions.
这是在泳池交易中返回的。
And pool transactions looks very much like the transactions message.
池交易看起来非常类似于交易消息。
Okay, that's historical data, pending data.
好的，这是历史数据，等待数据。
The last responsibility I wanted to mention on the P2P is accessing the state.
我想在P2P上提及的最后责任是访问州。
So a lot of people have probably heard about what's about SnapSync.
因此，很多人可能听说过Snapsync。
I just want to say quickly how SnapSync works.
我只想快速说出Snapsync的工作原理。
at a high level you can think about
在高水平上，您可以考虑
SnapSync as
snapsync as
a two-phase protocol
两相协议
the first phase being
第一阶段是
I need to download a bunch
我需要下载一堆
of data
数据
contiguously so if we
连续的话，如果我们
oops
糟糕
if we think
如果我们想
about the
关于
try
尝试
as
作为
some sort
某种
of Merkle tree.
默克尔树。
This diagram is just going to be a binary tree because it would be really difficult
该图只是一棵二进制树，因为这真的很困难
to draw.
画。
It'd be really difficult to draw a hex array tree in text.
在文本中绘制十六进制阵列树真的很困难。
I'm sure it's been done though.
我确定它已经完成了。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a B, C, D.
所以这是B，C，D。
Okay, so the way that SnapSync works is you first request the leaves of the tree against a certain root.
好的，所以Snapsync的工作方式是您首先要求树的叶子以某个根。
And so let's say this is root one.
因此，假设这是根。
So the root is changing.
因此根正在改变。
This is a very small example, but obviously there's, you know, I don't know, maybe millions, maybe 100 million different leaf nodes that we have to access.
这是一个很小的例子，但是显然，我不知道，也许是数百万，也许是我们必须访问的1亿个不同的叶子节点。
200 million leaf nodes that we have to access.
我们必须访问的2亿个叶子节点。
And so as we're going through this, we might access A and B against a root one.
因此，当我们经历这一点时，我们可能会访问a和b。
And then root one changes because nodes don't keep all of the historical state.
然后扎根一个变化，因为节点不能保留所有历史状态。
They only sort of keep that hot state, the active state.
他们只保留那种热状态，即活跃状态。
In Go Ethereum and in a lot of clients, that's around the last 128 states.
在Go Ethereum和许多客户中，这是最近128个州。
So if root 1 is for block, let's say 1, and now you need to access,
因此，如果root 1是用于块，则假设1，现在您需要访问，
now the blockchain has moved on.
现在，区块链已经继续前进。
The blockchain has moved on and it's now on 200.
区块链已经继续前进，现在是200。
These are going to be like totally different values.
这些将像完全不同的价值观。
So let's say that we downloaded this part of the trial.
假设我们下载了试用的这一部分。
We downloaded this left part of the trial.
我们下载了试验的左侧部分。
We got A and B.
我们有一个和B。
Now we're at block 200.
现在我们处于200号块。
It's taking a very long time for us to download these things.
我们花很长时间才下载这些东西。
We need to download C and D.
我们需要下载C和D。
C and D still have not changed.
C和D仍然没有改变。
We're able to download those.
我们可以下载这些。
And so now locally what we have is we have A, B, C, D.
因此，现在在当地我们拥有的是A，B，C，D。
and what we can see on our chain is that a and b do not match in in this root for block 200
我们可以在链上看到的是，A和B不符合该块200
and so now we need to go and we need to ask like what is the like updated values for this
因此，现在我们需要去，我们需要询问像这样的更新值是什么
so this first part of the snap protocol is just uh
因此，SNAP协议的第一部分只是UH
i don't know how to say this contiguous
我不知道该说这个连续
state retrieval.
国家检索。
So we're just going through and we're accessing every single leaf in order for the accounts. And
因此，我们只是在进行，我们正在访问每个叶子以获取帐户。和
this is like super simple. There's obviously the account try, then there's the storage try
这就像超级简单。显然有帐户尝试，然后有存储尝试
underneath it. But you would just go through, you would start the lowest indexed leaf node,
在下面。但是您只会通过，您将启动最低的索引叶节点，
download it, download the next one and go all the way through until you get to the end of the state.
下载它，下载下一个，然后一直穿过，直到到达州的尽头。
Once you get through the end of the state, you can see that you might have something that's stale.
一旦完成了州的尽头，您就会发现自己可能有些过时的东西。
so c and d are still valid but a and b are incorrect and so now you have to go through this
因此C和D仍然有效，但是A和B不正确，因此您必须经历此操作
this healing phase which if you run a geth node or any node that's doing snap sync the healing
这个康复阶段，如果您运行Geth节点或进行SNAP同步的任何节点
phase is probably the most confusing part so the healing phase is really just going through your
阶段可能是最令人困惑的部分
tree and trying to you know get the integrity of the state back so you're going to do a bypass
树并试图让您知道恢复状态的完整性，以便您要进行绕行
path lookup. And so you might ask, okay, get me the full list of nodes that are underneath
路径查找。因此，您可能会问，好吧，让我完整的节点列表
root 200. Let's put one and two here. So this healing phase might be like get R200.
root 200。让我们在这里放一个和两个。因此，这个康复阶段可能就像获得R200。
And that would return to you the nodes one and two, which are listed here. The next part is
这将返回您的节点一和两个节点，这些节点在此处列出。下一部分是
to get one.
得到一个。
And so that will list you R and A.
因此，这将列出您和A。
And you'll now notice that this path is exactly the same.
现在您会注意到这条路完全相同。
If you think about it in terms of a binary tree,
如果您用二进制树考虑一下，
the left node could be index zero.
左节点可能为索引零。
The left left node is index zero zero.
左左节点为索引零。
The left right node is like index zero one.
左右节点就像索引零一个。
And so those are the paths, zero zero, zero one.
因此，这些是零零，一个零的路径。
and you can see now that for 0, 0, you had A.
现在您可以看到，对于0，0，您有A。
You already had A, but it's telling you it's actually R.
您已经有一个了，但是告诉您实际上是R。
So you can update, we can now update our local state
因此您可以更新，我们现在可以更新我们的本地状态
to be R, A, C, D.
成为r，a，c，D。
And you would continue this healing process.
您将继续这个康复过程。
You would see that you had to update that,
您会看到您必须更新它，
but then you get down to 2.
但是随后您下降到2。
You say get 2,
你说得到2，
and you see that you already have cnd and that's all correct so there's no need to update at this
而且您会看到您已经拥有CND，这都是正确的，因此无需更新
point like healing is done uh this might be maybe difficult to conceptualize because it's such a
像康复一样的观点，这可能很难概念化，因为它是这样的
small example but if you extrapolate this to millions of nodes uh this is this could become
小例子，但是如果您将其推断到数百万节点，呃，这可能会变成
a very slow process and what's interesting is that the function of this process that matters is
一个非常缓慢的过程，有趣的是，这个过程的功能是
how fast you can download,
您可以下载多快，
how fast can you do this contiguous download?
您可以下载多快？
If you can do this,
如果你能做到这一点，
imagine you can do this contiguous download instantly
想象您可以立即下载此连续下载
and you download everything against R1.
然后您下载了针对R1的所有内容。
So you're able to download everything
因此，您可以下载所有内容
before R1 pivots out.
在R1枢转之前。
That means that you don't have to do any healing
这意味着您不必进行任何康复
because you have downloaded
因为您已经下载了
a complete state try against a certain route.
一个完整的状态试图反对某个路线。
Healing only has to occur
只需要康复
whenever you cannot complete the continuous state retrieval against the same route.
每当您无法完成相同路线的连续状态检索时。
And so you download some against R1, you download some against R200, some against R400,
因此，您下载了一些针对R1的下载，您下载了一些反对R200，有些针对R400，
and it goes on.
然后继续。
And so if you have a very slow internet connection, and it takes you a super long time to do the
因此，如果您的Internet连接非常缓慢，那么您需要很长时间才能完成
state retrieval, once you get to the healing phase, you have a ton of nodes that are out
州检索，一旦进入康复阶段，您就会有大量出现的节点
of date.
日期。
And so now you have to go through this very slow process of by path retrieval to go and download that data. And so that's why sometimes people are saying, like, why is my node stuck on healing?
因此，现在您必须经历一个非常缓慢的路径检索过程才能下载该数据。因此，这就是为什么有时人们会说我的节点会粘在治疗上的原因？
and that's typically what's happening.
这通常就是正在发生的事情。
Their node is trying to heal
他们的节点试图治愈
an extremely deformed state try.
一个极端变形的尝试。
And so sometimes it's better to just delete
因此，有时最好删除
the full database and try and start again
完整的数据库，尝试重新开始
with the contiguous state retrieval.
随着连续的状态检索。
And if maybe you had something wrong with your internet
而且，如果您的互联网有问题
or maybe your node was offline for a long time
也许您的节点很长一段时间脱机
and it has the contiguous state,
它具有连续状态，
but it has to do the healing,
但是它必须进行康复，
it's sometimes better just to download all the state once again and we don't have to go too
有时最好只下载所有州，我们也不必去
deeply into the different uh snap messages but it's all here uh this repo that i'm in is
深入介绍了不同的uh快照消息，但这一切都在这里
uh this repo is is in the ethereum organization so if you're curious about other parts of the
嗯，这个仓库在以太坊组织中，因此，如果您对
devpdp spec or want to dig look more into these things there's the ethereum slash devpdp repo
DEVPDP规格或想挖掘更多这些东西，有以太坊斜线DEVPDP repo
And if you're wanting more information on SnapSync,
如果您想了解Snapsync的更多信息，
this is the SnapSpec.
这是snapspec。
And the SnapSpec has a super good overview and description.
SNAPSPEC具有超级良好的概述和描述。
And it's definitely, I think it's definitely worth a read
绝对是，我认为绝对值得一读
if you're still kind of confused on exactly how SnapSync works.
如果您仍然对Snapsync的工作方式感到困惑。
Okay, that's P2P.
好吧，那是P2P。
Any questions related to P2P content?
有什么问题与P2P内容有关吗？
Thank you so much, Matt. That was awesome.
非常感谢，马特。那太棒了。
We already answered a few questions in the chat. It was mostly people asking,
我们已经在聊天中回答了一些问题。大多数人问，
how do you know you are not downloading a wrong chain when you, for example,
你怎么知道你没有下载错误的链条，例如
connect your network at bootstrap node is malicious? What happens then?
在引导节点上连接您的网络是恶意的吗？那会发生什么呢？
Yeah, in that case, these routes are authenticated routes.
是的，在这种情况下，这些路线是经过身份验证的路线。
So the way that you start doing SnapSync sort of looks like this.
因此，您开始进行Snapsync的方式看起来像这样。
So basically you start with your weak subjectivity checkpoint.
因此，基本上，您从弱主观性检查点开始。
how you get that values you know that's sort of up to each person but what most people do is they
您如何获得该价值观，您知道这取决于每个人，但是大多数人做的是
get some weak subjectivity checkpoint from some checkpoint server and that gives you a route
从某些检查点服务器获取一些弱主观性检查点，这为您提供了路线
let's see we'll just call it r and actually this is like a block hash so then you go and
让我们看看我们将其称为r，实际上这就像一个块哈希，然后你去
you get the block associated with the hash
您得到与哈希相关联的块
once you have the block associated with the hash you start snap against that blocks state
与哈希相关联的块后，您就可以开始按照该块状态进行快照
so what I'm trying to illuminate here is that the state root which you're running snap against
所以我想在这里阐明的是您正在运行的状态根源
has been authenticated by you in the sense that we trust this state root to be correct like you're
从您的意义上说，我们相信这种状态的根源是正确的，就像您一样
not verifying that the computation to get to that state root was correct you're assuming it was
不验证到达该状态根的计算是否正确，您假设是
correct and you're just going to download the state associated with it and
正确，您将下载与之相关的状态
you are kind of able to like continue doing this because we're not verifying the state.
您有点喜欢继续这样做，因为我们没有验证状态。
And so you're sort of seeing new blocks come in, you do header about verification on it.
因此，您有点看到新块进来，您可以在其中进行验证。
And if the headers are correct, you just assume those state routes are correct. So that's where
如果标题正确，则只需假设这些状态路线是正确的。那就是那里
the new routes come in. So you might have verified route one with your weak subjectivity checkpoint,
新路线进来。因此，您可能已经验证了一条路线，并具有弱主观性检查点，
it took you a long time to download this data, you eventually get to route to 200. And now you
您花了很长时间才下载此数据，最终您可以到达200。
You have a different route, but each time we're just trusting that route is correct.
您有不同的路线，但是每次我们都相信该路线是正确的。
And then the data that you're getting back has a witness against this route.
然后，您要回来的数据将对这条路线进行见证。
So if I ask for all of the accounts, all of the leaves from zero to one, it would return
因此，如果我要求所有帐户，所有叶子的所有叶子从零到一个，都会返回
a proof that proves that R is part of route 200, that A is part of route 200.
证明R是200号公路的一部分证明，A是200号公路的一部分。
So in this case, you're not going to get data that's not part of the route you're downloading.
因此，在这种情况下，您将不会获取不是要下载路线的一部分的数据。
really the only thing that could possibly happen is that the state was computed incorrectly
真的，唯一可能发生的事情是国家计算错误
and you're downloading some corrupted state that the chain has accepted it's extremely
而且您正在下载一些损坏的状态，即该连锁店已经接受了它非常非常
unlikely for that to happen because you know this is sort of this light client assumption
不太可能发生这种情况，因为您知道这是一个轻度的客户假设
that we have this economic majority verifying the chain if you don't want to rely on an economic
如果您不想依靠经济
majority, if you want to verify from Genesis or from the merge that a state is correct,
多数，如果您想从创世纪验证或合并状态是正确的，
you have to do a full sync. And so Snap has nothing to do with full sync. That's a totally
您必须做一个完整的同步。因此，Snap与完全同步无关。完全是一个
separate way of accessing the state. And that's where you start from the very beginning and you
单独的访问状态方式。这就是您从一开始就开始的地方
apply every single transaction that's ever occurred on Ethereum to eventually get to the
应用以太坊上发生过的每笔交易，最终到达
latest block and verify that the state of the latest block equals the state of all the transactions
最新块并验证最新块的状态是否等于所有交易的状态
that you applied.
您申请了。
Awesome.
惊人的。
Let's see, maybe there are
让我们看看，也许有
more questions, but we are at the time
更多问题，但我们当时正在
we should be wrapping up. It's been
我们应该结束。它已经
more than 90 minutes.
超过90分钟。
But yeah, amazing
但是，是的，很棒
fire, man. Thanks
火，伙计。谢谢
a lot.
很多。
It's really great inside.
里面真的很棒。
People love your
人们爱你
Vim setup, by the way.
顺便说一句，VIM设置。
They already found your .files repo
他们已经找到了您的.files仓库
to replicate it.
复制它。
This was a nice, yeah.
是的，这很好。
Yeah, thanks so much for having me.
是的，非常感谢您拥有我。
That's most of the things
那是大多数事情
that I want to talk about.
我想谈谈。
I don't think we really had
我认为我们真的没有
too much time
时间太多
to go super deeply
超级深入
into these things.
进入这些东西。
Hopefully you're able to see
希望你能看到
the different repos
不同的存储库
that I was accessing.
我正在访问。
The dead P2P repo,
死去的P2P回购，
the consensus specs repo those are things that have really good information that i recommend
共识规格回购这些是我建议的非常好的信息
people like digging more deeply into go ethereum's repo lots of good comments to read if you're
人们喜欢更深入地研究以太坊的回购，如果您是您的回购很多好的评论
curious about how some of the things that i was describing worked you can totally
好奇我描述的某些事情如何工作，您可以完全可以
go through that stuff and and see some see the documentation there the only other thing that i
浏览这些内容，然后看到一些文档，我唯一的另一件事
was thinking of talking about was the json rpc i would check out the execution apis repo it
在想谈论的是JSON RPC，我会检查执行API的回购
describes the interface for the execution layer.
描述执行层的接口。
When people think about what is Ethereum,
当人们想到什么是以太坊时
the JSON RPC is kind of Ethereum
JSON RPC是一种以太坊
in more or less absolute terms,
用或多或少的绝对术语
because that's the interface that people have
因为那是人们的界面
to access Ethereum.
访问以太坊。
So take a look at the execution APIs repo,
因此，看看执行API库，
and you can see all the data that is available
您可以看到所有可用的数据
to query for Ethereum.
查询以太坊。
Awesome, thanks a lot. I just want to ask one more thing, can you please share the notes,
太棒了，非常感谢。我只想问一件事，您能分享笔记吗？
the Overview doc that you created there with us, send it to us or edit it to the repo?
您与我们一起创建的概述文档，将其发送给我们或将其编辑给回购？
Yeah, I can do that.
是的，我可以做到。
Again, amazing job, I learned a lot myself, and seeing you go through all the important
再次，出色的工作，我自己学到了很多东西，看到您经历了所有重要的事情
it was great yeah i think people have a little to learn and uh also uh watch the recording again
很棒的是的，我认为人们有一点学习，呃，呃，呃，再次观看录音
so yeah um thanks a lot man i really appreciate it yeah feel free to tag me on i'm on the eps
是的，嗯，非常感谢，我真的很感激，是的，可以随时在EPS上标记我
discord so tag me at like clients if you have any more questions i'll try to get back to you
不一致，所以如果您还有其他问题，请在像客户一样给我标记，我会尝试与您联系
guys if i can awesome thanks so much matt appreciate it and uh for those of you who are
伙计们，我非常感谢Matt感谢它，并为您的那些人
in Denver for ETH Denver this week.
本周在丹佛（Denver）为ETH丹佛（Eth Denver）。
We will be hosting a meetup on Thursday.
我们将在星期四举办聚会。
You can check in the Discord for that information.
您可以在不和谐中查看该信息。
Yeah, once again, thanks a lot, Matt,
是的，再一次，非常感谢，马特，
and we'll see you all next week for Consensus Layer Overview
下周我们会见所有共识层概述
with Alex Stokes.
与亚历克斯·斯托克斯（Alex Stokes）。
Nice.
好的。
Thanks, guys.
谢谢，伙计们。
Take it easy.
别紧张。
Bye.
再见。